<?xml version="1.0" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE faqs SYSTEM "./dtd/faqs.dtd">

<faqs title="Building on Other Platforms">
    <faq title="Building &XercesCName; on OS/2 using Visual Age C++">
    <q>Building &XercesCName; on OS/2 using Visual Age C++</q>
    <a>
          <p>OS/2 is a favourite IBM PC platforms. The only
          option in this platform is to use
          <jump href="http://www-4.ibm.com/software/ad/vacpp/">Visual Age C++ compiler</jump>.
          Here are the steps you need to build &XercesCName; using
          Visual Age C++ on OS/2.</p>
          <s3 title="Building &XercesCName; library">
             <p><em>Requirements:</em></p>
                <ul>
                    <li>VisualAge C++ Version 4.0 with Fixpak 1:
                    <br/>Download the
                    <jump href="http://www-4.ibm.com/software/ad/vacpp/service/csd.html">Fixpak</jump>
                    from the IBM VisualAge C++ Corrective Services web page.</li>
                </ul>

             <p>There are two ways to build &XercesCName;. The "From Existing" method only
                  requires VAC++. The "From Scratch" method requires both Object Rexx and VAC++
                  installed.</p>

          <p><em>The &quot;From Existing&quot; Method</em></p>
          <ol>
            <li>In the <code>&XercesCSrcInstallDir;\Projects\OS2\VACPP40</code> directory,
            find and edit the VAC++ configuration file <code>project_options.icc</code>.</li>

            <li>Change the directory on the first line <code>'BASE_DIR = "..."'</code>
            to match the base directory of the &XercesCName; sources on your system.
            Note that the directory path must use double backslashes <code>"\\"</code>!</li>

            <li>Save <code>project_options.icc</code></li>

            <li>Start the Command Line in the VAC++ folder.</li>

            <li>Navigate to the <code>&XercesCSrcInstallDir;\Projects\OS2\VACPP40</code> directory.</li>

            <li>Run <code>build.cmd</code>. This does a migration build.</li>

            <li>When <code>build.cmd</code> finishes, review the file <code>compiler.errors</code>.
            This file should contain only informational messages, almost all complaining
            about constant values in comparisons.</li>

            <li>You should now have a <code>xerces-c.dll</code> and <code>xerces-c.lib</code>.
            The library file is an import library for the DLL.</li>
          </ol>

          <p><em>The &quot;From Scratch&quot; Method</em></p>
          <ol>
            <li>If you are not currently running <code>Object Rexx</code>,
            run the <code>SWITCHRX</code> command from a command line,
            answer <code>"yes"</code> to switching to <code>Object Rexx</code>, and follow the
            instructions to reboot. You can switch back to <code>"Classic Rexx"</code> by running
            <code>SWITCHRX</code> again. But you probably won't need to switch back since
            <code>Object Rexx</code> runs almost 100% of Classic Rexx programs.</li>

            <li>In the <code>&XercesCSrcInstallDir;\Projects\OS2\VACPP40</code> directory,
            run <code>genICC.cmd</code>. This builds the VAC++ configuration files for
            the sources you have on your system.</li>

            <li>Check the generated <code>ICC</code> files to ensure that they didn't pick up some
            non-OS/2 platform stuff. This happens when new platform-specific directories
            are added to Xerces. If they did pick up new non-OS/2 stuff, either edit it out
            of the <code>ICC</code> file or add them to the "ignore" array in <code>genICC.cmd</code> and
            re-run <code>genICC</code>.</li>

            <li>Start the Command Line in the VAC++ folder.</li>

            <li>Navigate to the <code>&XercesCSrcInstallDir;\Projects\OS2\VACPP40</code> directory.</li>

            <li>Run <code>build.cmd</code> This does a migration build.</li>

            <li>When <code>build.cmd</code> finishes, review the file <code>compiler.errors</code>.
            This file should contain only informational messages, almost all complaining about constant
            values in comparisons.</li>

            <li>You should now have a <code>xerces-c.dll</code> and <code>xerces-c.lib</code>.
            The library file is an import library for the DLL.)</li>

          </ol>

         <p><em>Packaging the Binaries</em></p>

          <p>There is an <code>Object Rexx</code> program that will package the binaries and headers.
          (See step 1 of the "From scratch" method on how to switch to <code>Object Rexx</code>.) The
          <code>packageBinaries.cmd</code> file is in the <code>&XercesCSrcInstallDir;\Projects\OS2\VACPP40</code>
          directory. Run <code>packageBinaries</code>, giving the source and target directories
          like this:</p>

<source>packageBinaries -s x:\&XercesCSrcInstallDir; -o x:\temp\&XercesCInstallDir;-os2</source>

          <p>(Match the source directory to your system; the target directory can be
          anything you want.)</p>

          <note>If you don't want to use the <code>Object Rexx</code> program, you'll need to
          manually  copy the "*.hpp" and "*.c" files to an include directory.
          (Be sure to maintain the same directory structure that you find under
          <code>&XercesCSrcInstallDir;</code>.)</note>
          </s3>
    </a>
    </faq>

    <faq title="Building &XercesCName; on AS/400">
    <q>Building &XercesCName; on AS/400</q>
    <a>
            <p>The following addresses the requirements and build of
           &XercesCName; natively on the AS/400.
            </p>
            <s3 title="Building &XercesCName; library">
                <p><em>Requirements:</em></p>

                <ul>
                    <li><code>QSHELL</code> interpreter installed (install base option 30, operating system)</li>
                    <li>QShell Utilities,  PRPQ  5799-XEH</li>
                    <li>ILE C++ for AS/400,  PRPQ 5799-GDW</li>
                    <li>GNU facilities  (the gnu facilities are currently available by request
                    only.  Send e-mail to <jump href="mailto:rchgo400@us.ibm.com">rchgo400@us.ibm.com</jump>)</li>
                </ul>

                <p><em>Recommendations:</em></p>

                <ul>
                <li>There are a couple of options when building the &XercesCName; parser on AS/400.
                For messaging support, you can use the in memory message option or the
                message file support. For code page translation, you can use the AS/400
                native <code>Iconv400</code> support or ICU. If you choose ICU, follow the instructions
                to build the ICU service program with the ICU download. Those instructions
                are not included here.</li>

                <li>Currently we recommend that you take the options of <code>MsgFile</code> and
                <code>Iconv400</code> (see below)</li>
                </ul>

                <p><em>Setup Instructions:</em></p>

                <ul>
                <li>Make sure that you have the requirements installed on your AS/400.
                We highly recommend that you read the writeup that accompanies the gnu
                facilities download.  There are install instructions as well as
                information about how modules, programs and service programs can be
                created in Unix-like fashion using gnu utilities.  Note that symbolic
                links are use in the file system to point to actual AS/400 <code>*module</code>,
                <code>*pgm</code> and <code>*srvpgm</code> objects in libraries.</li>
                <li>Download the tar file  (unix version) to the AS/400
                (using a mapped drive), and decompress and <code>untar</code> the source.
                We have had difficulty with the tar command on AS/400. This is under
                investigation.  If you have trouble, we recommend the following work
                around:</li></ul>
<source>qsh:
gunzip -d &lt;tar file.gz&gt;
pax -r -f &lt;uncompressed tar file&gt;</source>

                <ul>
                <li>Create AS400 target library. This library will be the target
                for the resulting  modules and  &XercesCName; service program. You will
                specify this library on the <code>OUTPUTDIR</code> environment variable
                in step 4</li>
                <li>Set up the following environment variables in your build process
                (use <code>ADDENVVAR</code> or <code>WRKENVVAR CL</code> commands):</li>
                </ul>
<source>XERCESCROOT - &lt;the full path to your &XercesCName; sources&gt;
PLATFORM  - 'OS400'
MAKE   - '/usr/bin/gmake'
OUTPUTDIR  - &lt;identifies target as400 library for *module, *pgm and *srvpgm objects&gt;
ICUROOT - (optional if using ICU)  &lt;the path of your ICU includes&gt;</source>

                <ul>
                <li>Add <code>QCXXN</code>, to your build process library list.
                This results in the resolution of <code>CRTCPPMOD</code> used by the
                <code>icc</code> compiler.</li>

                <li>The runConfigure instruction below uses <code>'egrep'</code>.
                This is not on the AS/400 but you can create it by doing the following:
                <code>edtf '/usr/bin/egrep'</code> with the following source:</li>
                </ul>

<source>#!/usr/bin/sh
/usr/bin/grep -e "$@"</source>

         <p>You may want to put the environment variables and library list
         setup instructions in a <code>CL</code> program so you will not forget these steps
         during your build.</p>

         <p><em>Configure</em></p>

         <p>To configure the make files for an AS/400 build do the following:</p>
<source>qsh
cd &lt;full path to &XercesCName;&gt;/src
runConfigure -p os400 -x icc -c icc -m MsgFile -t Iconv400</source>

         <p>Troubleshooting:</p>
<source>error: configure: error: installation or configuration problem:
C compiler cannot create executables.</source>

         <p>If during <code>runConfigure</code> you see the above error message, it
         can mean one of two things. Either <code>QCXXN</code> is not on your library
         list  <em>OR</em> the <code>runConfigure</code> cannot create the temporary
         modules (<code>CONFTest1</code>, etc) it uses to test out the compiler
         options. The second reason happens because the test modules already exist
         from a previous run of <code>runConfigure</code>. To correct the problem,
         do the following:</p>
<source>DLTMOD &lt;your OUTPUTDIR library&gt;/CONFT* and
DLTPGM your &lt;OUTPUTDIR library&gt;/CONFT*</source>

        <p><em>Build</em></p>

<source>qsh
gmake -e</source>

         <p>The above gmake will result in a service program being created
         in your specified library and a symbolic link to that service program
         placed in &lt;path to &XercesCName;/lib&gt;. You can either bind your
         XML application programs directly to the parser's service program
         via the <code>BNDSRVPGM</code> option on the <code>CRTPGM</code> or
         <code>CRTSRVPGM</code> command  or you can specify a binding directory
         on your <code>icc</code>  command. To specify an archive file to bind to,
         use the  <code>-L, -l</code> binding options on icc.  An archive file
         on AS/400 is a binding directory. To create an archive file, use
         <code>qar</code> command.  (see the gnu facilities write up).
         </p>

         <p>
         After building the &XercesCName; service program, create a binding directory
         by doing the following (note, this binding directory is used when building
         the samples):</p>
<source>qsh
cd &lt;full path to &XercesCName;>/lib&gt;
qar -cuv libxercesc1_1.a *.o
command = CRTBNDDIR BNDDIR(yourlib/libxercesc) TEXT('/yourlib/&XercesCName;/lib/libxercesc1_1.a')
command = ADDBNDDIRE BNDDIR(yourlib/libxercesc) OBJ((yourlib/LIBXERCESC *SRVPGM) )</source>


         <p><em>Troubleshooting:</em></p>
         <p>If you are on a V4R3 system, you will get a bind problem
         <code>'descriptor  QlgCvtTextDescToDesc not found'</code> using Iconv400.
         On V4R3 the system doesn't automatically pick up the <code>QSYS/QLGUSR</code> service
         program for you when resolving this function. This is not the case on V4R4.
         To fix this, you can either manually create the service program after creating
         all the resulting modules in your &lt;OUTPUTDIR&gt; library or you can create
         a symbolic link to a binding directory that points to  the <code>QLGUSR</code>
         service program and then specify  an additional <code>-L, -l</code> on the
         <code>EXTRA_LINK_OPTIONS</code> in <code>Makefile.incl</code>.
         See the <code>ln</code> and <code>qar</code> function in the gnu utilities.</p>

         <p>To build for transcoder ICU:</p>
         <ol>
          <li>Make sure you have an <code>ICUROOT</code> path set up so that you can
          find the ICU header files (usually <code>/usr/local</code>)</li>
          <li>Make sure you have created a binding directory (symbolic link)
          in the file system so that you can bind the &XercesCName; service program
          to the ICU service program and specify that on the <code>EXTRA_LINK_OPTIONS</code>
          in <code>src/Makefile.incl</code> (usually the default is a link
          in <code>/usr/local/lib</code>).</li>
         </ol>

         <p><em>Creating AS400 XML parser message file:</em></p>
         <p>As specified earlier, the <code>-m</code> MsgFile support on the
         <code>runConfigure</code> enable the parser messages to be pulled from
         an AS/400 message file. To view the source for creating  the message file
         and the XML parser messages, see the following stream file:</p>
<source>EDTF &lt;full path to &XercesCName;&gt;/src/util/MsgLoaders/MsgFile/CrtXMLMsgs</source>

         <p>In the prolog of <code>CrtXMLMsgs</code> there are instructions to create
         the message file:</p>
         <ol>
         <li>Use the <code>CPYFRMSTMF</code> to copy the CL source to an AS/400 source
         physical file. Note that the target source file needs to have record length
         of about 200 bytes to avoid any truncation.</li>
         <li>Create the CL program to create the message file and add the various
         message descriptions</li>
         <li>Call the CL program, providing the name of the message file
         (use <code>QXMLMSG</code> as default) and a library  (this can be any
         library, including any product library in which you wish to embed
         the xml parser)</li>
         </ol>

         <p>Note that the &XercesCName; source code for resolving parser messages is
         using by default message file  <code>QXMLMSG, *LIBL</code>.
         If you want to change either the message file name or explicitly qualify the
         library to match your product needs, you must edit the following <code>.cpp</code>
         files prior to your build.</p>
<source>&lt;full path to &XercesCName;&gt;/src/util/MsgLoaders/MsgFile/MsgLoader.cpp
&lt;full path to &XercesCName;&gt;/src/util/Platforms/OS400/OS400PlatformUtils.cpp</source>

         <p><em>Troubleshooting:</em></p>
         <p>If you are using the parser and are failing to get any  message text
         for error codes, it may be because of the <code>*LIBL</code> resolution of
         the message file.</p>
        </s3>

        <s3 title="Building Samples on AS/400">
<source>qsh
cd &lt;full path to &XercesCName;&gt;/samples
runConfigure -p os400 -x icc -c icc
gmake -e</source>

            <p><em>Troubleshooting:</em></p>
            <p>If you take a <code>'sed'</code> error, while trying to make the samples.
            This is an AS400 anomaly having to do with certain new line character and
            the <code>sed</code> function. A temporary work around is to use <code>EDTF</code>
            on the configure stream file (<code>../samples/configure</code>) and delete the
            following line near the bottom: <code>s%@DEFS@%$DEFS%g</code>.
            </p>

        </s3>
    </a>
    </faq>

    <faq title="Building &XercesCName; on Macintosh using CodeWarrior">
    <q>Building &XercesCName; on Macintosh using CodeWarrior</q>
    <a>
        <p>The following addresses the requirements and build of
           &XercesCName; Mactintosh using CodeWarrior.
        </p>

        <s3 title="Building &XercesCName; library">
            <p>The directions in this file cover installing and building
            &XercesCName; and ICU under the MacOS  using CodeWarrior.</p>
            <ol>
                <li><em>Create a folder:</em>
                    <br/>for the &XercesCName; and ICU distributions,
                    the "src drop" folder </li>

                <li><em>Download and uncompress:</em>
                    <br/>the ICU and &XercesCName; source distribution
                    <br/>the ICU and &XercesCName; binary distributions,
                    for the documentation included </li>

                <li><em>Move the new folders:</em>
                    <br/>move the newly created &XercesCName; and icu124
                    folders to the "src drop" folder.</li>

                <li><em>Drag and drop:</em>
                    <br/>the &XercesCName; folder into the "rename file" application located in
                    the same folder as this readme.
                    <br/>This is a MacPerl script that renames files that have
                    names too long to fit in a HFS/HFS+ filesystem.
                    It also searches through all of the source code and changes
                    the #include statements to refer to the new file names.</li>

                <li><em>Move the MacOS folder:</em>
                    <br/>from the in the Projects folder to "src drop:&XercesCName;:Projects".</li>

                <li><em>Open and build &XercesCName;:</em>
                    <br/>open the CodeWarrior project file
                    "src drop:&XercesCName;:Projects:MacOS:&XercesCName;:&XercesCName;"
                    and build the &XercesCName; library.</li>

                <li><em>Open and build ICU:</em>
                    <br/>open the CodeWarrior project file
                    "src drop:&XercesCName;:Projects:MacOS:icu:icu"
                    and build the ICU library.</li>

                <li><em>Binary distribution:</em>
                <br/>If you wish, you can create projects for and build the rest of the tools and test
                suites.  They are not needed if you just want to use &XercesCName;. I suggest that you
                use the binary data files distributed with the binary distribution of ICU instead of
                creating your own from the text data files in the ICE source distribution.</li>
            </ol>

            <p>There are some things to be aware of when creating your own
            projects using &XercesCName;.</p>
            <ol>
                <li>You will need to link against both the ICU and &XercesCName; libraries.</li>
                <li>The options "Always search user paths" and "Interpret DOS and Unix Paths" are
                    very useful.  Some of the code won't compile without them set.</li>
                <li>Most of the tools and test code will require slight modification to compile and run
                    correctly (typecasts, command line parameters, etc), but it is possible to get
                    them working correctly.</li>
                <li>You will most likely have to set up the Access Paths.  The access paths in the
                    &XercesCName; projects should serve as a good example.</li>
            </ol>


            <note>These instructions were originally contributed by
            <jump href="mailto:jbellardo@alumni.calpoly.edu">J. Bellardo</jump>.
            &XercesCName; has undergone many changes since these instructions
            were written. So, these instructions are not upto date.
            But it will give you a jump start if you are struggling to get it
            to work for the first time. We will be glad to get your changes.
            Please respond to the <jump href="mailto:&XercesCEmailAddress;">Xerces-C
            mailing list</jump> with your comments and corrections.</note>

        </s3>
    </a>
    </faq>
</faqs>
