<?xml version="1.0" encoding = "iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE faqs SYSTEM "./dtd/faqs.dtd">

<faqs title="Parsing with &XercesCName;">

  <faq title="Does &XercesCName; support Schema?">

    <q> Does &XercesCName; support Schema?</q>

    <a>

      <p>See <jump href="schema.html">the Schema page. </jump></p>

    </a>
  </faq>

  <faq title="Why &XercesCName; does not support this particular Schema feature?">

    <q> Why &XercesCName; does not support this particular Schema feature?</q>

    <a>

      <p> See <jump href="schema.html#supportedFeature">
         supported schema features in &XercesCName; &XercesCVersion;</jump></p>

    </a>
  </faq>

  <faq title="Why does my application crash on AIX when I run it under a
         multi-threaded environment?">

    <q>Why does my application crash on AIX when I run it under a
      multi-threaded environment?</q>

    <a>

      <p>AIX maintains two kinds of libraries on the system, thread-safe and
        non-thread safe. Multi-threaded libraries on AIX follow a different naming
        convention, Usually the multi-threaded library names are followed with "_r".
        For example, libc.a is single threaded whereas libc_r.a is multi-threaded.</p>

      <p>To make your multi-threaded application run on AIX, you <em>must</em>
        ensure that you do not have a "system library path" in your <code>LIBPATH</code>
        environment variable when you run the application. The appropriate
        libraries (threaded or non-threaded) are automatically picked up at runtime. An
        application usually crashes when you build your application for multi-threaded
        operation but don't point to the thread-safe version of the system libraries.
        For example, LIBPATH can be simply set as:</p>

<source>LIBPATH=$HOME/&lt;&XercesCProjectName;&gt;/lib</source>

      <p>Where &lt;&XercesCProjectName;&gt; points to the directory where the
        &XercesCProjectName; application resides.</p>

      <p>If, for any reason unrelated to &XercesCProjectName;, you need to keep a
        "system library path" in your LIBPATH environment variable, you must make sure
        that you have placed the thread-safe path before you specify the normal system
        path. For example, you must place <ref>/lib/threads</ref> before
        <ref>/lib</ref> in your LIBPATH variable. That is to say your LIBPATH may look
        like this:</p>

<source>export LIBPATH=$HOME/&lt;&XercesCProjectName;&gt;/lib:/usr/lib/threads:/usr/lib</source>

      <p>Where /usr/lib is where your system libraries are.</p>

    </a>
  </faq>

  <faq title="I cannot run the sample applications. What is wrong?">

    <q>I cannot run the sample applications. What is wrong?</q>

    <a>

      <p>In order to run an application built using &XercesCProjectName; you must
        set up your path and library search path properly. In the stand-alone version
        from Apache, you must have the &XercesCName; runtime library available from
        your path settings. On Windows this library is called <code>&XercesCWindowsDLL;.dll</code> which must be available from your <code>PATH</code> settings. (Note that now there are separate debug and release dlls for
        Windows. If the release dll is named <code>&XercesCWindowsDLL;.dll</code> then the debug dll is named <code>&XercesCWindowsDLL;d.dll)</code>. On UNIX platforms the library is called <code>&XercesCUnixLib;.so</code> (or <code>.a</code> or <code>.sl</code>) which must be available from your <code>LD_LIBRARY_PATH</code> (or <code>LIBPATH</code> or <code>SHLIB_PATH</code>) environment variable.</p>

      <p>Thus, if you installed your binaries under <code>$HOME/fastxmlparser</code>, you need to point your library path to that directory.</p>

<source>export LIBPATH=$LIBPATH:$HOME/fastxmlparser/lib # (AIX)
export LD_LIBRARY_PATH=$LD_LIBRARY_PATH:$HOME/fastxmlparser/lib # (Solaris, Linux)
export SHLIB_PATH=$SHLIB_PATH:$HOME/fastxmlparser/lib # (HP-UX)</source>

      <p>If you are using the enhanced version of this parser from IBM, you will
        need to put in two additional DLLs. In the Windows build these are <code>icuuc.dll</code> and <code>icudata.dll</code> which must be available from your PATH settings. On UNIX, these
        libraries are called <code>libicuuc.so</code> and <code>libicudata.so</code> (or <code>.sl</code> for HP-UX or <code>.a</code> for AIX) which must be available from your library search path.</p>

    </a>
  </faq>

  <faq title="I just built my own application using the &XercesCName; parser. Why does it crash?">

    <q>I just built my own application using the &XercesCName; parser. Why does
      it crash?</q>

    <a>

      <p>In order to work with the &XercesCName; parser, you have to first
        initialize the XML subsystem. The most common mistake is to forget this
        initialization. Before you make any calls to &XercesCName; APIs, you must
        call:</p>

<source>XMLPlatformUtils::Initialize():
try {
   XMLPlatformUtils::Initialize();
}
catch (const XMLException&amp; toCatch) {
   // Do your failure processing here
}</source>

      <p>This initializes the &XercesCProjectName; system and sets its internal
        variables. Note that you must the include <code>util/PlatformUtils.hpp</code> file for this to work.</p>

    </a>
  </faq>

  <faq title="Is &XercesCName; thread-safe?">

    <q>Is &XercesCName; thread-safe?</q>

    <a>

      <p>This is not a question that has a simple yes/no answer. Here are the
        rules for using &XercesCName; in a multi-threaded environment:</p>

      <p>Within an address space, an instance of the parser may be used without
        restriction from a single thread, or an instance of the parser can be accessed
        from multiple threads, provided the application guarantees that only one thread
        has entered a method of the parser at any one time.</p>

      <p>When two or more parser instances exist in a process, the instances can
        be used concurrently, without external synchronization. That is, in an
        application containing two parsers and two threads, one parser can be running
        within the first thread concurrently with the second parser running within the
        second thread.</p>

      <p>The same rules apply to &XercesCName; DOM documents. Multiple document
        instances may be concurrently accessed from different threads, but any given
        document instance can only be accessed by one thread at a time.</p>

      <p>DOMStrings allow multiple concurrent readers. All DOMString const
        methods are thread safe, and can be concurrently entered by multiple threads.
        Non-const DOMString methods, such as <code>appendData()</code>, are not thread safe and the application must guarantee that no other
        methods (including const methods) are executed concurrently with them.</p>

    </a>
  </faq>

  <faq title="Can't debug into the &XercesCName; DLL with the MSVC debugger">

    <q> The libs/dll's I downloaded keep me from using the debugger in VC6.0. I
      am using the 'D', debug versions of them. "no symbolic information found" is
      what it says. Do I have to compile everything from source to make it work?</q>

    <a>

      <p>Unless you have the .pdb files, all you are getting with the debug
        library is that it uses the debug heap manager, so that you can compile your
        stuff in debug mode and not be dangerous. If you want full symbolic info for
        the &XercesCName; library, you'll need the .pdb files, and to get those, you'll
        need to rebuild the &XercesCName; library.</p>

    </a>
  </faq>

  <faq title="First-chance exception in Microsoft debugger">

    <q>"First-chance exception in DOMPrint.exe (KERNEL32.DLL): 0xE06D7363:
      Microsoft C++ Exception." I am always getting this message when I am using the
      parser. My programs are terminating abnormally. Even the samples are giving
      this exception. I am using Visual C++ 6.0 with latest service pack
      installed.</q>

    <a>

      <p>&XercesCName; uses C++ exceptions internally, as part of its normal
        operation. By default, the MSVC debugger will stop on each of these with the
        "First-chance exception ..." message.</p>

      <p>To stop this from happening do this:</p>

      <ul>
        <li>start debugging (so the debug menu appears)</li>
        <li>from the debug menu select "Exceptions"</li>
        <li>from the box that opens select "Microsoft C++ Exception" and set it
          to "Stop if not handled" instead of "stop always".</li>
      </ul>

      <p>You'll still land in the debugger if your program is terminating
        abnormally, but it will be at your problem, not from the internal &XercesCName;
        exceptions.</p>

    </a>
  </faq>

  <faq title="I am seeing memory leaks in &XercesCName;. Are they real?">

    <q>I am seeing memory leaks in &XercesCName;. Are they real?</q>

    <a>

      <p>The &XercesCName; library allocates and caches some commonly reused
        items. The storage for these may be reported as memory leaks by some heap
        analysis tools; to avoid the problem, call the function <code>XMLPlatformUtils::Terminate()</code> before your application exits. This will free all memory that was being
        held by the library.</p>

      <p>For most applications, the use of <code>Terminate()</code> is optional. The system will recover all memory when the application
        process shuts down. The exception to this is the use of &XercesCName; from DLLs
        that will be repeatedly loaded and unloaded from within the same process. To
        avoid memory leaks with this kind of use, <code>Terminate()</code> must be called before unloading the &XercesCName; library</p>

    </a>
  </faq>

  <faq title="Can I validate the data contained in a DOM tree?">

    <q>Is there a facility in &XercesCName; to validate the data contained in a
      DOM tree? That is, without saving and re-parsing the source document?</q>

    <a>

      <p>No. This is a frequently requested feature, but at this time it is not
        possible to feed XML data from the DOM directly back to the DTD validator. The
        best option for now is to generate XML source from the DOM and feed that back
        into the parser.</p>

    </a>
  </faq>

  <faq title="Can I use Xerces to perform write validation">

    <q>Can I use Xerces to perform "write validation" (which is having an
      appropriate DTD and being able to add elements to the DOM whilst validating
      against the DTD)? Is there a function that I have totally missed that creates
      an XML file from a DTD, (obviously with the values missing, a skeleton, as it
      were.)</q>

    <a>

      <p>The answers are: "No" and "No." Write Validation is a commonly requested
        feature, but &XercesCName; does not have it yet.</p>

      <p>The best you can do for now is to create the DOM document, write it back
        as XML and re-parse it.</p>

    </a>
  </faq>

  <faq title="Why does my multi-threaded application crash on Solaris?">

    <q>Why does my multi-threaded application crash on Solaris?</q>

    <a>

      <p>The problem appears because the throw call on Solaris 2.6 is not
        multi-thread safe. Sun Microsystems provides a patch to solve this problem. To
        get the latest patch for solving this problem, go to
        <jump href="http://sunsolve.sun.com">SunSolve.sun.com</jump> and get the
        appropriate patch for your operating system. For Intel machines running
        Solaris, you need to get Patch ID 104678. For SPARC machines you need to get
        Patch ID #105591.</p>

    </a>
  </faq>

  <faq title="Why does my application gives unresolved linking errors on Solaris?">

    <q>Why does my application gives unresolved linking errors on Solaris?</q>

    <a>

      <p>On Solaris there are a few things that need to be done before you
        execute your application using &XercesCName;. In case you're using the
        binary build of &XercesCName; make sure that the OS and compiler are
        the same version as the ones used to build the binary. Different OS and
        compiler versions might cause unresolved linking problems or compilation
        errors. If the versions are different, rebuild the &XercesCName; library on
        your system before building your application. If you're using ICU (which is
        packaged with XML4C) you need to rebuild the compatible version of ICU
        first.</p>

      <p>Also check that the library path is set properly and that the correct
        versions of <code>gmake</code> and <code>autoconf</code> are on your system.</p>

    </a>
  </faq>

  <faq title="Why do I get Internal Compiler Error when compiling &XercesCName; for a 64bit target with gcc?">
    <q>Why do I get Internal Compiler Error when compiling &XercesCName; for a 64bit target with gcc?</q>
    <a>
      <p>This is a compiler problem.  Try turning off optimization to bypass the problem.</p>
    </a>
  </faq>


  <faq title="How are entity reference nodes handled in DOM?">

    <q>How are entity reference nodes handled in DOM?</q>

    <a>

      <p>If you are using the native DOM classes, the function <code>setExpandEntityReferences</code> controls how entities appear in the DOM tree. When
        setExpandEntityReferences is set to false (the default), an occurrence of an
        entity reference in the XML document will be represented by a subtree with an
        EntityReference node at the root whose children represent the entity expansion.
        Entity expansion will be a DOM tree representing the structure of the entity
        expansion, not a text node containing the entity expansion as text.</p>

      <p>If setExpandEntityReferences is true, an entity reference in the XML
        document is represented by only the nodes that represent the entity expansion.
        The DOM tree will not contain any entityReference nodes.</p>

    </a>
  </faq>

  <faq title="What kinds of URLs are currently supported in &XercesCName;?">

    <q>What kinds of URLs are currently supported in &XercesCName;?</q>

    <a>

      <p>The <code>XMLURL</code> class provides for limited URL support. It understands the <code>file://, http://</code>, and <code>ftp://</code> URL types, and is capable or parsing them into their constituent
        components, and normalizing them. It also supports the commonly required action
        of conglomerating a base and relative URL into a single URL. In other words, it
        performs the limited set of functions required by an XML parser.</p>

      <p>Another thing that URLs commonly do are to create an input stream that
        provides access to the entity referenced. The parser, as shipped, only supports
        this functionality on URLs in the form <code>file:///</code> and <code>file://localhost/</code>, i.e. only when the URL refers to a local file.</p>

      <p>You may enable support for HTTP and FTP URLs by implementing and
        installing a NetAccessor object. When a NetAccessor object is installed, the
        URL class will use it to create input streams for the remote entities referred
        to by such URLs.</p>

    </a>
  </faq>

  <faq title="How can I add support for URLs with HTTP/FTP protocols?">

    <q>How can I add support for URLs with HTTP/FTP protocols?</q>

    <a>

      <p>Support for the http: protocol is now included by default on all
        platforms.</p>

      <p>To address the need to make remote connections to resources specified
        using additional protocols, ftp for example, &XercesCName; provides the <code>NetAccessor</code> interface. The header file is <code>src/util/XMLNetAccessor.hpp</code>. This interface allows you to plug in your own implementation of URL
        networking code into the &XercesCName; parser.</p>

    </a>
  </faq>

  <faq title="Can I use &XercesCName; to parse HTML?">

    <q>Can I use &XercesCName; to parse HTML?</q>

    <a>

      <p>Yes, but only if the HTML follows the rules given in the
        <jump href="http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-xml">XML specification</jump>. Most HTML,
        however, does not follow the XML rules, and will generate XML well-formedness
        errors.</p>

    </a>
  </faq>

  <faq title="I keep getting an error: &quot;invalid UTF-8 character&quot;. What's wrong?">

    <q>I keep getting an error: "invalid UTF-8 character". What's wrong?</q>

    <a>

      <p>Most commonly, the XML <code>encoding =</code> declaration is either incorrect or missing. Without a declaration, XML
        defaults to the use utf-8 character encoding, which is not compatible with the
        default text file encoding on most systems.</p>

      <p>The XML declaration should look something like this:</p>

      <p><code>&lt;?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?&gt;</code></p>

      <p>Make sure to specify the encoding that is actually used by file. The
        encoding for "plain" text files depends both on the operating system and the
        locale (country and language) in use.</p>

      <p>Another common source of problems is that some characters are not
        allowed in XML documents, according to the XML spec. Typical disallowed
        characters are control characters, even if you escape them using the Character
        Reference form. See the <jump href="http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-xml#charsets">XML
        spec</jump>, sections 2.2 and 4.1 for details. If the parser is generating an <code>Invalid character (Unicode: 0x???)</code> error, it is very likely that there's a character in there that you
        can't see. You can generally use a UNIX command like "od -hc" to find it.</p>

    </a>
  </faq>

  <faq title="What encodings are supported by Xerces-C / XML4C?">

    <q>What encodings are supported by Xerces-C / XML4C?</q>

    <a>

      <p>Xerces-C has intrinsic support for ASCII, UTF-8, UTF-16 (Big/Small
        Endian), UCS4 (Big/Small Endian), EBCDIC code pages IBM037 and IBM1140
        encodings, ISO-8859-1 (aka Latin1) and Windows-1252. This means that it can
        parse input XML files in these above mentioned encodings.</p>

      <p>XML4C -- the version of Xerces-C available from IBM -- extends this
        set to include the encodings listed in the table below.</p>

      <table>
        <tr>
          <td><em>Common Name</em></td>
          <td><em>Use this name in XML</em></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>8 bit Unicode</td>
          <td>UTF-8</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>ISO Latin 1</td>
          <td>ISO-8859-1</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>ISO Latin 2</td>
          <td>ISO-8859-2</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>ISO Latin 3</td>
          <td>ISO-8859-3</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>ISO Latin 4</td>
          <td>ISO-8859-4</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>ISO Latin Cyrillic</td>
          <td>ISO-8859-5</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>ISO Latin Arabic</td>
          <td>ISO-8859-6</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>ISO Latin Greek</td>
          <td>ISO-8859-7</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>ISO Latin Hebrew</td>
          <td>ISO-8859-8</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>ISO Latin 5</td>
          <td>ISO-8859-9</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>EBCDIC US</td>
          <td>ebcdic-cp-us</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>EBCDIC with Euro symbol</td>
          <td>ibm1140</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>Chinese, PRC</td>
          <td>gb2312</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>Chinese, Big5</td>
          <td>Big5</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>Cyrillic</td>
          <td>koi8-r</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>Japanese, Shift JIS</td>
          <td>Shift_JIS</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>Korean, Extended UNIX code</td>
          <td>euc-kr</td>
        </tr>
      </table>

      <p>Some implementations or ports of Xerces-C provide support for
        additional encodings. The exact set will depend on the supplier of the parser
        and on the character set transcoding services in use.</p>

    </a>
  </faq>

  <faq
  title="What character encoding should I use when creating XML documents?">

    <q>What character encoding should I use when creating XML documents?</q>

    <a>

      <p>The best choice in most cases is either utf-8 or utf-16. Advantages of
        these encodings include:</p>

      <ul>
        <li>The best portability. These encodings are more widely supported by
          XML processors than any others, meaning that your documents will have the best
          possible chance of being read correctly, no matter where they end up.</li>
        <li>Full international character support. Both utf-8 and utf-16 cover the
          full Unicode character set, which includes all of the characters from all major
          national, international and industry character sets.</li>
        <li>Efficient. utf-8 has the smaller storage requirements for documents
          that are primarily composed of of characters from the Latin alphabet. utf-16 is
          more efficient for encoding Asian languages. But both encodings cover all
          languages without loss.</li>
      </ul>

      <p>The only drawback of utf-8 or utf-16 is that they are not the native
        text file format for most systems, meaning that common text file editors and
        viewers can not be directly used.</p>

      <p>A second choice of encoding would be any of the others listed in the
        table above. This works best when the xml encoding is the same as the default
        system encoding on the machine where the XML document is being prepared,
        because the document will then display correctly as a plain text file. For UNIX
        systems in countries speaking Western European languages, the encoding will
        usually be iso-8859-1.</p>

      <p>The versions of Xerces distributed by IBM, both C and Java (known
        respectively as XML4C and XML4J), include all of the encodings listed in the
        above table, on all platforms.</p>

      <p>A word of caution for Windows users: The default character set on
        Windows systems is windows-1252, not iso-8859-1. While &XercesCName; does
        recognize this Windows encoding, it is a poor choice for portable XML data
        because it is not widely recognized by other XML processing tools. If you are
        using a Windows-based editing tool to generate XML, check which character set
        it generates, and make sure that the resulting XML specifies the correct name
        in the <code>encoding="..."</code> declaration.</p>

    </a>
  </faq>

  <faq
  title="I find memory leaks in &XercesCName;. How do I eliminate it?">

    <q>I find memory leaks in &XercesCName;. How do I eliminate it?</q>

    <a>

      <p>The "leaks" that are reported through a leak-detector or heap-analysis
        tools aren't really leaks in most application, in that the memory usage does
        not grow over time as the XML parser is used and re-used.</p>

      <p>What you are seeing as leaks are actually lazily evaluated data
        allocated into static variables. This data gets released when the application
        ends. You can make a call to <code>XMLPlatformUtil::terminate()</code> to release all the lazily allocated variables before you exit your
        program.</p>

    </a>
  </faq>

  <faq title="Is EBCDIC supported?">

    <q>Is EBCDIC supported?</q>

    <a>

      <p>Yes, &XercesCName; supports EBCDIC. When creating EBCDIC encoded XML
        data, the preferred encoding is ibm1140. Also supported is ibm037 (and its
        alternate name, ebcdic-cp-us); this encoding is almost the same as ibm1140, but
        it lacks the Euro symbol.</p>

      <p>These two encodings, ibm1140 and ibm037, are available on both
        Xerces-C and IBM XML4C, on all platforms.</p>

      <p>On IBM System 390, XML4C also supports two alternative forms,
        ibm037-s390 and ibm1140-s390. These are similar to the base ibm037 and ibm1140
        encodings, but with alternate mappings of the EBCDIC new-line character, which
        allows them to appear as normal text files on System 390s. These encodings are
        not supported on other platforms, and should not be used for portable data.</p>

      <p>XML4C on System 390 and AS/400 also provides additional EBCDIC
        encodings, including those for the character sets of different countries. The
        exact set supported will be platform dependent, and these encodings are not
        recommended for portable XML data.</p>

    </a>
  </faq>

  <faq title="How to write out a DOM tree into an XML file?">
     <q>How to write out a DOM tree into an XML file?</q>
     <a>
      <p>This feature is not yet availabe in the parser. Take a look at the DOMPrint sample
         for an example on parsing  XML file, then writing it out back to the screen. You
         can use that code.</p>
    </a>
  </faq>

  <faq title="Is it OK to call the XMLPlatformUtils::Initialize/Terminate pair of routines multiple times in one program?">
    <q>Is it OK to call the XMLPlatformUtils::Initialize/Terminate pair of routines multiple times in one program?</q>
    <a>
      <p>No.  XMLPlatformUtils::Initialize() can only be called once per process. Call
         Initialize() when you start and Terminate() when you end.</p>
    </a>
  </faq>

  <faq title="Why does deleting a transcoded string result in assertion on windows?">
    <q>Why does deleting a transcoded string result in assertion on windows?</q>
    <a>
      <p>Both your application program and the Xerces DLL must use the same *DLL* version of the
         runtime library.  If either statically links to the runtime library, the
		 problem will still occur.

         For example, for a Win32/VC6 build, the runtime library build setting MUST
		 be "Multithreaded DLL" for release builds and "Debug Multithreaded DLL" for
		 debug builds.</p>
    </a>
  </faq>

  <faq title="How do I transcode to/from something besides the local code page?">
    <q>How do I transcode to/from something besides the local code page?</q>
    <a>
      <p>XMLString::transcode() will transcode from XMLCh to the local code page, and
         other APIs which take a char* assume that the source text is in the local
         code page. If this is not true, you must transcode the text yourself. You
         can do this using local transcoding support on your OS, such as Iconv on
         Unix or or IBM's ICU package. However, if your transcoding needs are simple,
         you can achieve some better portability by using the Xerces parser's
         transcoder wrappers. You get a transcoder like this:
       </p>
       <ul>
		 <li>
         1. Call XMLPlatformUtils::fgTransServer->MakeNewTranscoderFor() and provide
            the name of the encoding you wish to create a transcoder for. This will
            return a transcoder to you, which you own and must delete when you are
            through with it.

           NOTE: You must provide a maximum block size that you will pass to the transcoder
           at one time, and you must blocks of characters of this count or smaller when
           you do your transcoding. The reason for this is that this is really an
           internal API and is used by the parser itself to do transcoding. The parser
           always does transcoding in known block sizes, and this allows transcoders to
           be much more efficient for internal use since it knows the max size it will
           ever have to deal with and can set itself up for that internally. In
           general, you should stick to block sizes in the 4 to 64K range.
         </li>
		 <li>
         2. The returned transcoder is something derived from XMLTranscoder, so they
            are all returned to you via that interface.
         </li>
		 <li>
         3. This object is really just a wrapper around the underlying transcoding
            system actually in use by your version of Xerces, and does whatever is
            necessary to handle differences between the XMLCh representation and the
            representation uesd by that underying transocding system.
         </li>
		 <li>
         4. The transcoder object has two primary APIs, transcodeFrom() and
            transcodeTo(). These transcode between the XMLCh format and the encoding you
            indicated.
         </li>
		 <li>
         5. These APIs will transcode as much of the source data as will fit into the
            outgoing buffer you provide. They will tell you how much of the source they
            ate and how much of the target they filled. You can use this information to
            continue the process until all source is consumed.
         </li>
		 <li>
         6. char* data is always dealt with in terms of bytes, and XMLCh data is
            always dealt with in terms of characters. Don't mix up which you are dealing
            with or you will not get the correct results, since many encodings don't
            have a one to one relationship of characters to bytes.
         </li>
		 <li>
         7. When transcoding from XMLCh to the target encoding, the transcodeTo()
            method provides an 'unrepresentable flag' parameter, which tells the
            transcoder how to deal with an XMLCh code point that cannot be converted
            legally to the target encoding, which can easily happen since XMLCh is
            Unicode and can represent thousands of code points. The options are to use a
            default replacement character (which the underlying transcoding service will
            choose, and which is guaranteed to be legal for the target encoding), or to
            throw an exception.
         </li>
       </ul>
    </a>
  </faq>

  <faq title="Why DOM_Node::cloneNode() does not clone the pointer assigned to a DOM_Node via DOM_Node::setUserData()?">
    <q>Why DOM_Node::cloneNode() does not clone the pointer assigned to a DOM_Node via DOM_Node::setUserData()?</q>
    <a>
      <p>There are several possible options for how cloneNode should handle userData:
      </p>
      <ul>
      <li>
          1) Copy the pointer. May be a Very Bad Idea if you really wanted the data
           associated with a particular node object.
      </li>
      <li>
          2) Clone the object being pointed at. Maybe a Very Bad Idea if that object,
          in turn, wasn't designed to be cloned at this time.
      </li>
      <li>
          3) A complex call-back API has been proposed which would allow the userData
          object to tell the DOM which of these three options should be taken, but
          that would require that only objects implementing that API be registered as
          userData. That doesn't seem to be a good option.
      </li>
      <li>
          4) Do nothing. This is by far the lowest-overhead and safest choice. And
          since cloneNode is a DOM operation, and userData is _not_ defined by the
          standard DOM API, one can make a very strong case for this being the "most
          correct" option.
      </li>
      </ul>
      <p>
          We chose (4), very deliberately. If you want one of the others, you can
          implement it by creating your own wrapper operation for cloneNode() and
          calling that.
      </p>
      <p>
          NOTE that userData should be considered a nonportable, experimental feature
          of the Xerces DOM. It may evaporate entirely in favor of a scheme based on
          the DOM Level 3 "node key" mechanism, when that becomes officially
          available.
      </p>
    </a>
  </faq>

</faqs>
