<?xml version="1.0" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE faqs SYSTEM "./dtd/faqs.dtd">

<faqs title="Other &XercesCName; Questions">

    <faq title="I can't use C++. Do you have a Java version?">
        <q>I can't use C++. Do you have a Java version?</q>
        <a>

            <p>Yes. The Xerces family of products also has a Java
            version.  More information is available at: <jump
            href="http://xml.apache.org/xerces-j/index.html">http://xml.apache.org/xerces-j/index.html</jump></p>

        </a>
    </faq>


    <faq title="I found a defect - how do I report it?">
        <q>I found a defect - how do I report it?</q>
        <a>

            <p>Send the defect reports to &lt;<jump
            href="mailto:&XercesCEmailAddress;">
            &XercesCEmailAddress;</jump>&gt; with the version number,
            the exact OS release number, the compiler version number,
            and a copy of the XML document that generates the
            error. Do mention the archive (source or binary) you are
            using. If you have rebuilt the samples/library then please
            mention that too. The more information we get, the faster
            we will be able to reproduce and fix the defect.</p>

        </a>
    </faq>


    <faq title="Is there any kind of support available for Xerces-C/XML4C?">
        <q>Is there any kind of support available for Xerces-C/XML4C?</q>
        <a>

            <p>Limited support is available with <em>no
            guarantees</em> via the Xerces-C mailing list &lt;<jump
            href="mailto:&XercesCEmailAddress;">&XercesCEmailAddress;</jump>&gt;
            and <jump
            href="http://www.alphaworks.ibm.com/forum/xml4c.nsf/discussion_current_frameset">XML4C
            discussion forum on Alphaworks</jump>. We strongly
            recommend all &XercesCName; users to subscribe to the
            Xerces-C mailing list and monitor the discussions on the
            XML4C discussion forums.</p>

            <p>IBM, in the past, has set up some separate special
            support contracts for customers who absolutely insisted on
            having support. If you have similar requirements, then you
            may contact IBM via email at <jump
            href="mailto:xml4c@us.ibm.com">xml4c@us.ibm.com</jump>.</p>

        </a>
    </faq>


    <faq title="I have a question not covered here -- who may I contact?">
        <q>I have a question not covered here -- who may I contact?</q>
        <a>

            <p>Hopefully, you have read this entire FAQ and still
            could not find the answer to your question.</p>

            <p>Next, we would like you to search the archives
            (addresses given below) and on going discussion threads
            (URL's mentioned in the answer to the previous question
            above) to see if someone else has already asked the same
            question. Its been a while since the first public release
            of this product was made, so most common questions have
            been asked and answered. Many people actively
            subscribe/monitor these lists and is the fastest way to
            get an answer.</p>

            <p>The Apache's Xerces-C mailing list is archived at <jump
            href="http://xml-archive.webweaving.org">http://xml-archive.webweaving.org</jump>.</p>

            <p>The archives for IBM's XML4C discussion forum are
            available at <jump
            href="http://www.alphaworks.ibm.com/forum/xml4c.nsf/discussion_archived_frameset">here</jump>.</p>

            <p>If you are using XML4C then you may also send your
            question to <jump
            href="mailto:xml4c@us.ibm.com">xml4c@us.ibm.com</jump>. Do note
            that the packaging and bundling of XML4C sources and
            binaries differs from whats available at the Apache's
            site, so please address your questions accordingly. Again,
            the response from this email address may not be as prompt
            as what you may receive from the mailing lists/discussion
            forums.</p>

            <p>Its critical, that you very clearly mention the
            following information along with your question. The
            product name, version, source/binary archive that you
            downloaded, whether you rebuilt the samples/library or are
            using the stock ones that we release, platform, OS version
            number, compiler, compiler version number.</p>

        </a>
    </faq>

</faqs>

