<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE faqs SYSTEM "sbk:/style/dtd/faqs.dtd">
<faqs title="Other &XercesCName; Questions">

  <faq title="Are the Xerces parsers Year-2000-compliant?">
        <q>Are the Xerces parsers Year-2000-compliant?</q>
        <a>
           	<p>Yes, Xerces-J and Xerces-C are Year 2000 compliant.
		They do not currently use any dates at all (at least until the XML
		Schema date datatypes are fully supported).  However, you may still
		have Y2K problems if the underlying OS or Java implementation has
		problems with dates past year 2000 (e.g. OS calls which accept or
		return year numbers).</p>
		<p>Most (UNIX) systems store dates internally as signed 32-bit
		integers which contain the number of seconds since 1st January 1970,
		so the magic boundary to worry about is the year 2038 and not 2000.
		But modern operating systems shouldn't cause any trouble at all.</p>
		
		<p>The Apache Xerces project is an open-source software product
		of the Apache Software Foundation. The project and the Foundation
		cannot and does not offer legal assurances regarding any suitability
		of the software for your application. There are several commercial
		support organizations and derivative products available that may be
		able to certify the software and provide you with any assurances you
		may require (IBM's Websphere product is one of them).</p>
		<p>The Apache HTTP server software is distributed with the following
		disclaimer, found in the software license: 	</p>
<source>THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED ``AS IS'' AND ANY EXPRESSED OR IMPLIED
WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES
OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE ARE
DISCLAIMED.  IN NO EVENT SHALL THE APACHE SOFTWARE FOUNDATION OR
ITS CONTRIBUTORS BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL,
SPECIAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT NOT
LIMITED TO, PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOSS OF
USE, DATA, OR PROFITS; OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION) HOWEVER CAUSED AND
ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY,
OR TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT
OF THE USE OF THIS SOFTWARE, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF
SUCH DAMAGE.</source>
        </a>
  </faq>

  <faq title="How do I determine the version of &XercesCName; I am using?">
        <q>How do I determine the version of &XercesCName; I am using?</q>
        <a>

           <p>The version string for &XercesCName; is in one of the header files. Look
           inside the file <code>src/xercesc/util/XercesVersion.hpp</code> or, in the binary distribution,
           look in <code>include/xercesc/utils/XercesVersion.hpp</code>. </p>

           <p>If you don't have the header files, you have to find the version
           information from the shared library name. On Windows right click on
           the DLL name &XercesCWindowsDLL;.dll in the bin directory and look up
           properties. The version information may be found on the Version tab.</p>

           <p>On AIX, just look for the library name &XercesCUnixLib;&XercesCUnixSoName;.so (or
           &XercesCUnixLib;.so.&XercesCUnixSoName; on Solaris/Linux
           and &XercesCUnixLib;.sl.&XercesCUnixSoName; on HP-UX). The
           version number is indicated in the name of the library.</p>
        </a>
  </faq>

  <faq title="I can't use C++. Do you have a Java version?">

    <q>I can't use C++. Do you have a Java version?</q>

    <a>

      <p>Yes. The Xerces family of products also has a Java version. More
        information is available at:
        <jump href="http://xml.apache.org/xerces2-j/index.html">
        http://xml.apache.org/xerces2-j/index.html</jump></p>

    </a>
  </faq>


  <faq title="Where can I find additional information on XML?">

    <q>Where can I find additional information on XML?</q>

    <a>

    <p>The Web. <jump href="http://www.oasis-open.org/cover/xml.html">
      http://www.oasis-open.org/cover/xml.html</jump> is an excellent place to start,
      with links to overviews, FAQs, specifications, industry news, applications and
      other software, related standards, etc.</p>

    </a>
  </faq>

  <faq title="Is there any kind of support available for &XercesCName;?">

    <q>Is there any kind of support available for &XercesCName;?</q>

    <a>

    <p>&XercesCName; comes with <em>no</em> formal support.</p>

      <p>Every volunteer project obtains its strength from the people involved in
        it. Mailing lists provide a simple and effective communication mechanism. You
        are welcome to join any of these mailing lists (or all of them if you wish).
        You can choose to lurk, or to actively participate. It's up to you. Before you
        join these lists, you should look over the resources in the Reference Library
        section</p>

      <p>Instructions for subscribing are at
        <jump
         href="http://xml.apache.org/mail.html">http://xml.apache.org/mail.html</jump>.
        Archives of the lists are available from
        <jump href="http://marc.theaimsgroup.com/?l=xerces-c-dev">
        http://marc.theaimsgroup.com/?l=xerces-c-dev</jump>
        </p>

    </a>
  </faq>

  <faq title="I found a defect -- how do I report it?">

    <q>I found a defect -- how do I report it?</q>

    <a>

      <p>See <jump href="bug-report.html">Bug Reporting</jump>.
      </p>

    </a>
  </faq>

  <faq title="I have a patch to the &XercesCName; source code. How do I submit it?">

    <q>I have a patch to the &XercesCName; source code. How do I submit it?</q>

    <a>

      <p>Mail it to the <jump href="mailto:&XercesCEmailAddress;">&XercesCName;
        mailing list</jump>. There are no set rules about
        how or what must be included -- if you've fixed a problem or enhanced the code
        in some way, we really would like to get your changes, and will take them in
        any reasonable form.</p>

      <p>Generally a diff of the changed files against the current sources from
        CVS is good, along with some kind of description of what the change is.
        (Working with the current sources is important!)</p>

    </a>
  </faq>

  <faq title="Where can I get predefined character entity definitions?">

    <q>Where can I get predefined character entity definitions??</q>

    <a>

    <p> Download <jump href="http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml1/xhtml1.zip">
      http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml1/xhtml1.zip. </jump></p>

    </a>
  </faq>

  <faq title="Does &XercesCName; support XPath?">

    <q> Does &XercesCName; support XPath?</q>

    <a>

      <p>No.  The &XercesCName; &XercesCVersion; only has partial XPath implementation
         for the purposes of handling Schema identity constraints.  For full XPath
         support, you can refer
         <jump href="http://xml.apache.org/xalan-c/overview.html">Apache Xalan C++</jump> or
         other Open Source Projects like
         <jump href="http://software.decisionsoft.com">Pathan</jump>.
       </p>

    </a>
  </faq>

</faqs>
