<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE faqs SYSTEM "sbk:/style/dtd/faqs.dtd">

<faqs title="Distributing &XercesCName;">

	<faq title="Which DLL's do I need to distribute with my application?">
		<q>Which DLL's do I need to distribute with my application?</q>
		<a>
			<p>There are currently two configurations in which Xerces-C binaries
			are published. One is from the Apache site, while the other is
			from the IBM Alphaworks Site.</p>
			
			<p>The <jump href="http://xml.apache.org/dist">Apache download
			site</jump> binary drops only contain support for ASCII, UTF-8, UTF-16
			and UCS4 encodings. The parser intrinsically supports transcoding
			input files in these encodings to Unicode (all internal processing in
			the parser happens in Unicode).  If you are using these Xerces-C
			binaries in your application, then you only need to distribute
			<em>one</em> file:<br></br>
			&XercesCWindowsLib;.dll for Windows NT/95/98, or<br/>
			&XercesCUnixLib;.a for AIX, or<br/>
			&XercesCUnixLib;.so for Solaris/Linux, or<br/>
			&XercesCUnixLib;.sl for HP-UX.</p>
			
			<p>However, if your application needs to support more international
			encodings, other than the one's mentioned above, then you may use the
			XML4C binaries published by IBM at their 
			<jump href="http://www.alphaworks.ibm.com/tech/xml4c">AlphaWorks</jump>
			site.  XML4C binaries use and include 
			<jump href="http://www10.software.ibm.com/developerworks/opensource/icu/index.html">IBM
			Classes for Unicode</jump> (ICU) (also an open source project but under 
			<jump href="http://www10.software.ibm.com/developerworks/opensource/license10.html">IBM
			Public License</jump>) for transcoding and as a result can parse input
			files in over 100 different encodings. If you are using XML4C binaries
			in your application, then in <em>addition</em> to the &XercesCName; library
			file mentioned above, you also need to ship:</p>
	
			<ol>
				<li><em>ICU shared library file</em>:<br></br>
					icuuc.dll for Windows NT/95/98, or<br></br>
					libicu-uc.a for AIX, or<br></br>
					libicu-uc.so for Solaris/Linux, or<br></br>
					libicu-uc.sl for HP-UX.</li>
				<li><em>ICU converter files</em>: *.cnv.<br></br>
					These are platform specific binary files which contain the tables used
					to transcode characters from the respective encoding to Unicode. These
					files may be found in the 'lib/icu/data' directory of the XML4C binary
					archives.</li>
			</ol>
		</a>
	</faq>

	<faq title="How do I package the sources to create a binary drop?">
	
		<q>How do I package the sources to create a binary drop?</q>
		
		<a>
			<p>You have to first compile the sources inside your IDE to
			create the required DLLs and EXEs. Then you need to copy
			over the binaries to another directory for the binary
			drop. A perl script has been provided to give you a jump
			start. You need to install perl on your machine for the script to work.
			The file may not work if you have changed your
			source tree. You have to modify the script to suit
			your current state of the source tree. To invoke the
			script, go to the \&lt;&XercesCProjectName;&gt;\scripts directory, and type:</p>
<source>perl packageBinaries.pl</source>

			<p>You will get a message that looks like: </p>

<source>Usage is: packageBinaries &lt;options&gt;
options are:  -s &lt;source_directory&gt;
              -o &lt;target_directory&gt;
              -c &lt;C compiler name&gt; (e.g. gcc or xlc)
              -x &lt;C++ compiler name&gt; (e.g. g++ or xlC)
              -m &lt;message loader&gt; can be 'inmem', 'icu' or 'iconv'
              -n &lt;net accessor&gt; can be 'fileonly' or 'libwww'
              -t &lt;transcoder&gt; can be 'icu' or 'native'
              -r &lt;thread option&gt; can be 'pthread' or 'dce' (only used on HP-11)
              -h to get help on these commands
Example: perl packageBinaries.pl -s$HOME/xerces-c_1_0_0 
                                 -o$HOME/xerces-c_1_0_0 
								 -cgcc -xg++ -minmem 
								 -nfileonly -tnative</source>

			<p>Make sure that your compiler can be invoked from the command line and
			follow the instructions to produce a binary drop.</p>
		</a>
	</faq>
	
	<faq title="When will a port to my platform be available?">
	
		<q>When will a port to my platform be available?</q>
		
		<a>
			<p>Ports to other platforms are planned, but dates are not
			fixed yet. In the meantime, look below to see a
			description of the steps you need to follow to port it to
			another platform.</p>
			
			<p>We strongly encourage you to submit the changes that were
			required to make it work on another platform. We will
			incorporate these changes in the source code base and make
			them available in the future releases.</p>
			
			<p>All such changes may be sent to: &lt;
			<jump href="mailto:&XercesCEmailAddress;">&XercesCEmailAddress;</jump>&gt;.</p>
		</a>
	</faq>

	<faq title="How can I port &XercesCProjectName; to my favourite platform?">
		<q>How can I port &XercesCProjectName; to my favourite platform?</q>
		<a>
			<p>All platform dependent code in &XercesCProjectName; has been isolated to
			a couple of files, which should ease the porting effort.
			Here are the basic steps that should be followed to port
			&XercesCProjectName;.</p>
			
			<ol>
				<li>The directory 'src/util/Platforms' contains the
					platform sensitive files while 'src/util/Compilers' contains all
					development environment sensitive files. Each
					operating system has a file of its own and each
					development environment has another one of its own too.
					<br/>As an example, the Win32 platform as a Win32Defs.hpp file
					and the Visual C++ environment has a <code>VCPPDefs.hpp</code> file.
					These files set up certain define tokens, typedefs,
					constants, etc... that will drive the rest of the code to
					do the right thing for that platform and development
					environment. AIX/CSet have their own <code>AIXDefs.hpp</code> and
					<code>CSetDefs.hpp</code> files, and so on. You should create new
					versions of these files for your platform and environment
					and follow the comments in them to set up your own.
					Probably the comments in the Win32 and Visual C++ will be
					the best to follow, since that is where the main
					development is done.</li>
				
				<li>Next, edit the file XML4CDefs.hpp , which is where all
					of the fundamental stuff comes into the system. You will
					see conditional sections in there where the above
					per-platform and per-environment headers are brought in.
					Add the new ones for your platform under the appropriate
					conditionals.</li>
			
				<li>Now edit 'AutoSense.hpp'. Here we set canonical &XercesCProjectName;
					internal #define tokens which indicate the platform and
					compiler. These definitions are based on known platform
					and compiler defines.
					<br/>
					AutoSense.hpp is included in XML4CDefs.hpp and the
					canonical platform and compiler settings thus defined will
					make the particular platform and compiler headers to be
					the included at compilation.
					<br/>
					It might be a little tricky to decipher this file so be
					careful. If you are using say another compiler on Win32,
					probably it will use similar tokens so that the platform
					will get picked up already using what is already there.</li>
				
				<li>Once this is done, you will then need to implement a
					version of the 'platform utilities' for your platform.
					Each operating system has a file which implements some
					methods of the XMLPlatformUtils class, specific to that
					operating system. These are not terribly complex, so it
					should not be a lot of work. The Win32 verions is called
					Win32PlatformUtils.cpp, the AIX version is
					AIXPlatformUtils.cpp and so on. Create one for your
					platform, with the correct name, and empty out all of the
					implementation so that just the empty shells of the
					methods are there (with dummy returns where needed to make
					the compiler happy.) Once you've done that, you can start
					to get it to build without any real implementation.</li>
				
				<li>Once you have the system building, then start
					implementing your own platform utilties methods. Follow
					the comments in the Win32 version as to what they do, the
					comments will be improved in subsequent versions, but they
					should be fairly obvious now. Once you have these
					implementations done, you should be able to start
					debugging the system using the demo programs.</li>
			</ol>
			<p>That is the work required in a nutshell!</p>
		</a>
	</faq>
	
	<faq title="What application did you used to create the documentation?">
		<q>What application did you used to create the documentation?</q>
		<a>
			<p>We have used an internal XML based application to create the
			documentation. The documentation files are all written in XML and the
			application, internally codenamed StyleBook, makes use of XSL to transform
			it into an HTML document that you are seeing right now.
			It is currently available on the 
			<jump href="http://xml.apache.org/">Apache</jump> open source website as 
			<jump href="http://xml.apache.org/cocoon/index.html">Cocoon</jump>.</p>
			
			<p>The API documentation is created using 
			<jump href="http://www.zib.de/Visual/software/doc++/index.html">DOC++</jump>.</p>	
		</a>
	</faq>

	<faq title="Source code for the C++ Builder TreeViewer?">
		<q>Can I get the source code for the C++ Builder TreeViewer application?</q>
		<a>
			<p>In view of the numerous requests that we have received for
			the TreeViewer sample application (written using C++
			Builder), we have decided to make it available as an
			independent download from the IBM
			<jump href="http://www.alphaworks.ibm.com/tech/xml4c/">AlphaWorks</jump>
            portal. The archive to get from the 'Download' page is
            'DOMSampleTreeViewer.zip'. Please note, this is provided on a
            "as-is, no support" basis. This sample works with XML4C 2.3.1
            and we have not verified if it works with XML4C 3.x releases.</p>
			
			<p>TreeViewer parses the XML file, using &XercesCProjectName;,
			and displays the data as a tree.</p>
					
			<p>We welcome your additional feedback at: &lt;
			<jump href="mailto:&XercesCEmailAddress;">&XercesCEmailAddress;</jump>&gt;</p>
		</a>
	
	</faq>
	<faq title="Can I use &XercesCProjectName; in my product?">
		<q>Can I use &XercesCProjectName; in my product?</q>
		<a>
			<p>Yes! Read the license agreement first and contact us at
			&lt;<jump href="mailto:&XercesCEmailAddress;">&XercesCEmailAddress;</jump>&gt; 
			if you need assistance.</p>
		</a>
</faq>
</faqs>

