<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE faqs SYSTEM "./dtd/faqs.dtd">

<faqs title="Other &XercesCName; Questions">

    <faq title="I can't use C++. Do you have a Java version?">
        <q>I can't use C++. Do you have a Java version?</q>
        <a>

            <p>Yes. The Xerces family of products also has a Java
            version.  More information is available at: <jump
            href="http://xml.apache.org/xerces-j/index.html">http://xml.apache.org/xerces-j/index.html</jump></p>

        </a>
    </faq>



    <faq title="What are the differences between Xerces-C and IBM XML4C?">
        <q>"What are the differences between Xerces-C and IBM XML4C?"</q>
        <a>
            <p>XML4C from IBM is based on the Xerces-C code.  The
               only difference is that XML4C is bundled together
               with IBM's ICU classes for Unicode support, which
               allow it to support a wider range of character
               set encodings.</p>
        </a>
    </faq>
    <faq title="Is there any kind of support available for Xerces-C/XML4C?">
        <q>Is there any kind of support available for Xerces-C/XML4C?</q>
        <a>

            <p>&XercesCFullName; somes with <em>no</em> formal support.  </p>
            <p>Every volunteer project obtains its strength from the
            people involved in it. Mailing lists provide a simple and
            effective communication mechanism.   You are welcome to join
            any of these mailing lists (or all of them if you wish).
            You can choose to lurk, or actively participate. It's up to you.
            Before you join these lists, you should look over the resources
            in the Reference Library section</p>


            <p>Instructions for subscribing and list archives are
            <jump href="http://xml.apache.org/mail.html">here</jump>.
            </p>
            <p>
            IBM also maintains a newsgroup for discussion of XML4C.  The
            news server is "news.alphaworks.ibm.com", and the group is
            "XML-for-C++".</p>
        </a>
    </faq>

    <faq title="Where can I find additional information on XML?">
    <q>Where can I find additional information on XML?</q>
    <a>
        <p>The Web.  <jump href="http://www.oasis-open.org/cover/xml.html">
        http://www.oasis-open.org/cover/xml.html</jump> is an excellent
        place to start, with links to overviews, FAQs, specifications,
        industry news, applications and other software, related standards,
        etc.</p>
    </a>
    </faq>

    <faq title="I found a defect - how do I report it?">
        <q>I found a defect - how do I report it?</q>
        <a>

            <p>Check the bug list at
            <jump href="http://xml.apache.org/xerces-c/index.html">Apache</jump>.
            The problem may already be known, or even fixed.
           </p>

            <p>Otherwise, send the bugs to either the xerces-c-dev
            mailing list (preferred) or the IBM Alphaworks news group, as
            desribed above.  The more information that you can provide,
            the better the chance of understanding what happened, or
            what the problem really is.  Please include the version of Xerces-c or XML4C,
            what kind of machine, including Operating System and OS Verion Number,
            whether you built the xerces library yourself or used the binary distribution,
            the XML document (or excerpt) that fails, the C++ application code that failed,
            and what happened.
            </p>

        </a>
    </faq>




    <faq title="I have a patch to the Xerces C source code.  How do I submit it?">
        <q>I have a patch to the Xerces C source code.  How do I submit it?</q>
        <a>
            <p>Mail it to the xerces-c-dev mailing list at Apache  (You must be
               a subscriber to post to this list, but if you're considering changing
               the code you really want to be.)  There are no set
               rules about how or what must be included - if you've fixed a problem
               or enhanced the code in some way, we really would like to get the
               changes back and will take them in any reasonable form.</p>

            <p>Generally a diff of the changed files against the current sources
               from CVS is good, along with some kind of description of what the
               change is.  (Working with the current sources is important)</p>

        </a>
    </faq>


    <faq title="How do I port Xerces-C to a new platform?">
    <q>How do I port Xerces-C to a new platform?</q>
    <a>
        <p>(from Dean Roddey) The primary work of a port involved creating:</p>

        <ol>
        <li>A new compiler header for the compiler</li>
        <li>A new platform utilities file that implements the little bit of system
        access we need, and an associated header.</li>
        <li>Updating XercesDefs.hpp and AutoSense.hpp to get your new headers
        included when compiled under your OS and compiler.</li>
        </ol>

        <p>Other concerns are:</p>

        <ol>
        <li>Does ICU compile on your platform? If not, then you'll need to do a
        transcoder implementation that uses your local transcoding services. I
        assume that the Iconv transcoder would work for you, though perhaps with
        some modifications.</li>

        <li>What message loader will you use. For starting off, you can use the 'in
        memory' one which is very simple and easy. Then, once you get going, you'll
        want to possibly adapt the message catalog message loader or write one of
        your own that uses local services of some sort.</li>
        </ol>

    </a>
    </faq>

</faqs>

