<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE faqs SYSTEM "dtd/faqs.dtd">
<faqs title="Other &XercesCName; Questions">

  <faq title="How do I determine the version of &XercesCName; I am using?">
        <q>How do I determine the version of &XercesCName; I am using?</q>
        <a>

           <p>The version string for &XercesCName; is in one of the header files. Look
           inside the file <code>src/util/XercesDefs.hpp</code> or, in the binary distribution, look in <code>include/utils/XercesDefs.hpp</code>. Search for the static variable <code>gXercesFullVersionStr</code> and look at its definition. (It is usually a string like "1_4_0" or
           something similar). This is the version of &XercesCName; you are using.</p>

           <p>If you don't have the header files, you have to find the version
           information from the shared library name. On Windows NT/95/98 right click on
           the DLL name &XercesCWindowsLib;.dll in the bin directory and look up
           properties. The version information may be found on the Version tab.</p>

           <p>On AIX, just look for the library name &XercesCUnixLib;.a (or
           &XercesCUnixLib;.so on Solaris/Linux and &XercesCUnixLib;.sl on HP-UX). The
           version number is coded in the name of the library.</p>
        </a>
  </faq>

  <faq title="I can't use C++. Do you have a Java version?">

    <q>I can't use C++. Do you have a Java version?</q>

    <a>

      <p>Yes. The Xerces family of products also has a Java version. More
        information is available at:
        <jump href="http://xml.apache.org/xerces-j/index.html">
        http://xml.apache.org/xerces-j/index.html</jump></p>

    </a>
  </faq>


  <faq title="Where can I find additional information on XML?">

    <q>Where can I find additional information on XML?</q>

    <a>

    <p>The Web. <jump href="http://www.oasis-open.org/cover/xml.html">
      http://www.oasis-open.org/cover/xml.html</jump> is an excellent place to start,
      with links to overviews, FAQs, specifications, industry news, applications and
      other software, related standards, etc.</p>

    </a>
  </faq>

  <faq title="Is there any kind of support available for &XercesCName;?">

    <q>Is there any kind of support available for &XercesCName;?</q>

    <a>

    <p>&XercesCName; comes with <em>no</em> formal support.</p>

      <p>Every volunteer project obtains its strength from the people involved in
        it. Mailing lists provide a simple and effective communication mechanism. You
        are welcome to join any of these mailing lists (or all of them if you wish).
        You can choose to lurk, or to actively participate. It's up to you. Before you
        join these lists, you should look over the resources in the Reference Library
        section</p>

      <p>Instructions for subscribing are at
        <jump
         href="http://xml.apache.org/mail.html">http://xml.apache.org/mail.html</jump>.
        Archives of the lists are available from
        <jump href="http://archive.covalent.net">http://archive.covalent.net</jump>
        </p>

    </a>
  </faq>

  <faq title="I found a defect -- how do I report it?">

    <q>I found a defect -- how do I report it?</q>

    <a>

      <p>Check the bug list at the
        <jump href="http://xml.apache.org/xerces-c/index.html">Apache Xerces-C Web
        site</jump>. The problem may already be known, or even fixed. </p>

      <p>Otherwise, send the bugs to the <jump href="mailto:&XercesCEmailAddress;">
        Xerces-C mailing list</jump>. The more
        information that you provide, the better our chance of understanding what
        happened, or what the problem really is. Please include:</p>

      <ul>
        <li>The version of &XercesCName;</li>
        <li>What kind of machine</li>
        <li>Operating system and OS version number</li>
        <li>Whether you built the &XercesCName; library yourself or used the
          binary distribution</li>
        <li>The XML document (or excerpt) that fails</li>
        <li>The C++ application code that failed</li>
        <li>What happened</li>
      </ul>

    </a>
  </faq>

  <faq title="I have a patch to the &XercesCName; source code. How do I submit it?">

    <q>I have a patch to the &XercesCName; source code. How do I submit it?</q>

    <a>

      <p>Mail it to the <jump href="mailto:&XercesCEmailAddress;">Xerces-C
        mailing list</jump> at Apache. (You must be a
        subscriber to post to this list. But if you're considering changing the code
        you really want to be a subscriber, in any case.) There are no set rules about
        how or what must be included -- if you've fixed a problem or enhanced the code
        in some way, we really would like to get your changes, and will take them in
        any reasonable form.</p>

      <p>Generally a diff of the changed files against the current sources from
        CVS is good, along with some kind of description of what the change is.
        (Working with the current sources is important!)</p>

    </a>
  </faq>
</faqs>
