<?xml version="1.0" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE s1 SYSTEM "sbk:/style/dtd/document.dtd">

<s1 title="Experimental IDOM Programming Guide">
    <anchor name="IDOMProgGuide"/>
    <p>The experimental IDOM API is a new design of the C++ DOM API.
       Please note that this experimental IDOM API is only a prototype
       and is subject to change.</p>

    <anchor name="ConstructIDOMParser"/>
    <s2 title="Constructing a parser">
      <p>In order to use &XercesCName; to parse XML files using IDOM, you
        will need to create an instance of the IDOMParser class. The example
        below shows the code you need in order to create an instance of the
        IDOMParser.</p>

      <source>
int main (int argc, char* args[]) {

    try {
        XMLPlatformUtils::Initialize();
    }
    catch (const XMLException&amp; toCatch) {
        cout &lt;&lt; "Error during initialization! :\n"
             &lt;&lt; DOMString(toCatch.getMessage()) &lt;&lt; "\n";
        return 1;
    }

    char* xmlFile = "x1.xml";
    IDOMParser* parser = new IDOMParser();
    parser->setValidationScheme(IDOMParser::Val_Always);    // optional.
    parser->setDoNamespaces(true);    // optional

    ErrorHandler* errHandler = (ErrorHandler*) new HandlerBase();
    parser->setErrorHandler(errHandler);

    try {
        parser->parse(xmlFile);
    }
    catch (const XMLException&amp; toCatch) {
        cout &lt;&lt; "Exception message is: \n"
             &lt;&lt; DOMString(toCatch.getMessage()) &lt;&lt; "\n" ;
        return -1;
    }
    catch (const SAXParseException&amp; toCatch) {
        cout &lt;&lt; "Exception message is: \n"
             &lt;&lt; DOMString(toCatch.getMessage()) &lt;&lt; "\n" ;
        return -1;
    }
    catch (...) {
        cout &lt;&lt; "Unexpected Exception \n" ;
        return -1;
    }

    return 0;
}
      </source>
    </s2>

    <anchor name="DOMandIDOM"/>
    <s2 title="Comparision of C++ DOM and IDOM">
      <p>
        This section outlines the differences between the C++ DOM and IDOM APIs.
      </p>
    </s2>

    <anchor name="Motivation"/>
    <s2 title="Motivation behind new design">
      <p>
        The performance of the C++ DOM has not been as good as it
        might be, especially for use in server style applications.
        The DOM's reference counted automatic memory management has
        been the biggest time consumer. The situation becomes worse
        when running multi-threaded applications.
      </p>
      <p>
        The experimental C++ IDOM is a new alternative to the C++ DOM, and aims at
        meeting the following requirements:
      </p>
      <ul>
      <li>Reduced memory footprint.</li>
      <li>Fast.</li>
      <li>Good scalability on multiprocessor systems.</li>
      <li>More C++ like and less Java like.</li>
      </ul>
    </s2>

    <anchor name="IDOMClassNames"/>
    <s2 title="Class Names">
      <p>
        The IDOM class names are prefixed with "IDOM_". The intent is
        to prevent conflicts between IDOM class names and DOM class names
        that may already be in use by an application or other
        libraries that a DOM based application must link with.
      </p>


      <source>
IDOM_Document*   myDocument;   // IDOM
IDOM_Node*       aNode;
IDOM_Text*       someText;
      </source>

      <source>
DOM_Document     myDocument;   // DOM
DOM_Node         aNode;
DOM_Text         someText;
      </source>
    </s2>

    <anchor name="IDOMObjMgmt"/>
    <s2 title="Objects Management">
      <p>Applications would use normal C++ pointers to directly access the
         implementation objects for Nodes in IDOM C++, while they would use
         object references in DOM C++.
      </p>

      <p>Consider the following code snippets</p>


      <source>
// IDOM C++
IDOM_Node*       aNode;
IDOM_Node* docRootNode;
aNode = someDocument->createElement("ElementName");
docRootNode = someDocument->getDocumentElement();
docRootNode->appendChild(aNode);
      </source>

      <source>
// DOM C++
DOM_Node       aNode;
DOM_Node docRootNode;
aNode = someDocument.createElement("ElementName");
docRootNode = someDocument.getDocumentElement();
docRootNode.appendChild(aNode);
      </source>
   </s2>


    <anchor name="IDOMMemMgmt"/>
    <s2 title="Memory Management">
      <p>The C++ IDOM implementation no longer uses reference counting for
         automatic memory management.  The C++ IDOM uses an independent storage
         allocator per document.  The storage for a DOM document is
         associated with the document node object.
         The advantage here is that allocation would require no synchronization
         in most cases (based on the the same threading model that we
         have now - one thread active per document, but any number of
         documents running in parallel with separate threads).
      </p>

      <p>The allocator does not support a delete operation at all - all
         allocated memory would persist for the life of the document, and
         then the larger blocks would be returned to the system without separately
         deleting all of the individual nodes and strings within the document.
      </p>

      <p>The C++ DOM and IDOM are similar in the use of factory methods in the
         document class for all object creation. They differ in the object deletion
         mechanism.
      </p>

      <p>In C++ DOM, there is no explicit object deletion. The deallocation of
         memory is automatically taken care of by the reference counting.
      </p>

      <p>In C++ IDOM, there is an implict and explict object deletion.
      </p>
    </s2>

    <anchor name="IDOMMemImplicit"/>
      <s2 title="Implicit Object Deletion">
         <p>When parsing a document using an IDOMParser, all memory allocated
            for a DOM tree is associated to the DOM document.  And this storage
            will be automatically deleted when the parser instance is deleted (implicit).
         </p>
         <p>If you do multiple parse using the same IDOMParser instance, then
            multiple DOM documents will be generated and saved in a vector pool.
            All these documents (and thus all the allocated memory) won't be deleted
            until the parser instance is destroyed.  If you want to release the memory
            back to the system but don't want to destroy the IDOMParser instance at this moment,
            then you can call the method IDOMParser::resetDocumentPool to reset the document
            vector pool, provided that you do not need access to these documents anymore.
         </p>

         <p>Consider the following code snippets: </p>

         <source>
   // C++ IDOM - implicit deletion
   IDOMParser* parser = new IDOMParser();
   parser->parse(xmlFile)
   IDOM_Document *doc = parser->getDocument();

   unsigned int i = 1000;
   while (i > 0) {
      parser->parse(xmlFile)
      IDOM_Document* myDoc = parser->getDocument();
      i--;
   }

   // all allocated memory associated with these 1001 DOM documents
   // will be deleted implicitly when the parser instance is destroyed
   delete parser;
         </source>

         <source>
   // C++ IDOM - implicit deletion
   // optionally release the memory
   IDOMParser* parser = new IDOMParser();
   unsigned int i = 1000;
   while (i > 0) {
      parser->parse(xmlFile)
      IDOM_Document *doc = parser->getDocument();
      i--;
   }

   // instead of waiting until the parser instance is destroyed,
   // user can optionally choose to release the memory back to the system
   // if does not need access to these 1000 parsed documents anymore.
   parser->resetDocumentPool();

   // now the parser has some fresh memory to work on for the following
   // big loop
   i = 1000;
   while (i > 0) {
      parser->parse(xmlFile)
      IDOM_Document *doc = parser->getDocument();
      i--;
   }
   delete parser;

         </source>
      </s2>

    <anchor name="IDOMMemExplicit"/>
      <s2 title="Explicit Object Deletion">
      <p>If user is manually building a DOM tree in memory using the document factory methods,
         then the user needs to explicilty delete the document object to free all the allocated memory.
         It normally falls under the following 3 scenarios:
      </p>
        <ul>
           <li>If a user is manually creating a DOM document using the document implementation
               factory methods, IDOM_DOMImplementation::getImplementation()->createDocument,
               then the user needs to explicilty delete the document object to free all
               allocated memory. </li>
           <li>If a user is creating a DocumentType object using the document implementation factory
               method, IDOM_DOMImplementation::getImplementation()->createDocumentType, then
               the user also needs to explicilty delete the document type object to free the
               allocated memory.</li>
           <li>Special case:  If a user is creating a DocumentType using the document
               implementation factory method, and clone the node WITHOUT assigning a document
               owner to that documentType object, then the cloned node also needs to be explicitly
               deleted.</li>
        </ul>

      <p>Consider the following code snippets: </p>

      <source>
// C++ IDOM - explicit deletion
// use the document implementation factory method to create a document type and a document
IDOM_DocumentType* myDocType;
IDOM_Document*   myDocument;
IDOM_Node*       root;
IDOM_Node*       aNode;

myDocType  = IDOM_DOMImplementation::getImplementation()->createDocumentType(name, 0, 0);
myDocument = IDOM_DOMImplementation::getImplementation()->createDocument(0, name, myDocType);
root       = myDocument->getDocumentElement();
aNode      = myDocument->createElement(anElementname);

root->appendChild(aNode);

// need to delete both myDocType and myDocument which are created through DOM Implementation
delete myDocType;
delete myDocument;
      </source>

      <source>
// C++ IDOM - explicit deletion
// use the document implementation factory method to create a document
IDOM_DocumentType* myDocType;
IDOM_Document*   myDocument;
IDOM_Node*       root;
IDOM_Node*       aNode;

myDocument = IDOM_DOMImplementation::getImplementation()->createDocument();
myDocType  = myDocument->createDocumentType(name);
root       = myDocument->createElement(name);
aNode      = myDocument->createElement(anElementname);

myDocument->appendChild(myDocType);
myDocument->appendChild(root);
root->appendChild(aNode);

// the myDocType is created through myDocument, not through Document Implementation
// thus no need to delete myDocType
delete myDocument;
      </source>

      <source>
// C++ IDOM - explicit deletion
// manually build a DOM document
// clone the document type object which does not have an owner yet
IDOM_DocumentType* myDocType1;
IDOM_DocumentType* myDocType;
IDOM_Document*   myDocument;
IDOM_Node*       root;
IDOM_Node*       aNode;

myDocType  = IDOM_DOMImplementation::getImplementation()->createDocumentType(name, 0, 0);
myDocType1 = (IDOM_DocumentType*) myDocType->cloneNode(false);
myDocument = IDOM_DOMImplementation::getImplementation()->createDocument(0, name, myDocType);

root       = myDocument->getDocumentElement();
aNode      = myDocument->createElement(anElementname);

root->appendChild(aNode);

// myDocType does not have an owner yet when myDocType1 was cloned.
// thus need to explicitly delete myDocType1
delete myDocType1;
delete myDocType;
delete myDocument;
      </source>

      <source>
// C++ IDOM - explicit deletion
// manually build a DOM document
// clone the document type object that has an owner already
//   thus no need to delete the cloned object
IDOM_DocumentType* myDocType1;
IDOM_DocumentType* myDocType;
IDOM_Document*   myDocument;
IDOM_Node*       root;
IDOM_Node*       aNode;

myDocType  = IDOM_DOMImplementation::getImplementation()->createDocumentType(name, 0, 0);
myDocument = IDOM_DOMImplementation::getImplementation()->createDocument(0, name, myDocType);
myDocType1 = (IDOM_DocumentType*) myDocType->cloneNode(false);

root       = myDocument->getDocumentElement();
aNode      = myDocument->createElement(anElementname);

root->appendChild(aNode);

// myDocType already has myDocument as the owner when myDocType1 was cloned
// thus NO need to explicitly delete myDocType1
delete myDocType;
delete myDocument;
      </source>
      </s2>

      <p>Key points to remember when using the C++ IDOM classes:</p>

      <ul>
        <li>The DOM objects are accessed via C++ pointers.</li>

        <li>The DOM objects - nodes, attributes, CData
        sections, etc., are created with the factory methods
        (create...) in the document class.</li>

        <li>If you are manually building a DOM tree in memory, you
        need to explicitly delete the document object.
        Memory management will be automatically taken care of by
        the IDOM parser when parsing an instance document.</li>

      </ul>

    <anchor name="DOMStringXMCh"/>
    <s2 title="DOMString vs. XMLCh">
      <p>The IDOM C++ no longer uses DOMString to pass string data to
      and from the DOM API. Instead, the IDOM C++ uses plain, null-terminated
      (XMLCh *) utf-16 strings. The (XMLCh*) utf-16 type string is much
      simpler with lower overhead. All the string data would remain in
      memory until the document object is deleted.</p>

    <source>
//C++ IDOM
const XMLCh* nodeValue = aNode->getNodeValue();
    </source>

    <source>
//C++ DOM
DOMString    nodeValue = aNode.getNodeValue();
    </source>
    </s2>

</s1>
