<?xml version="1.0" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE s1 SYSTEM "sbk:/style/dtd/document.dtd">

<s1 title="SAX2 Programming Guide">

    <anchor name="ConstructParser2"/>
    <s2 title="Constructing an XML Reader">
      <p>In order to use &XercesCName; to parse XML files, you will
        need to create an instance of the SAX2XMLReader class. The example
        below shows the code you need in order to create an instance
        of SAX2XMLReader. The ContentHandler and ErrorHandler instances
        required by the SAX API are provided using the DefaultHandler
        class supplied with &XercesCName;.</p>

<source>
#include &lt;xercesc/sax2/SAX2XMLReader.hpp>
#include &lt;xercesc/sax2/XMLReaderFactory.hpp>
#include &lt;xercesc/sax2/DefaultHandler.hpp>
#include &lt;xercesc/util/XMLString.hpp>

int main (int argc, char* args[]) {

    try {
        XMLPlatformUtils::Initialize();
    }
    catch (const XMLException&amp; toCatch) {
        char* message = XMLString::transcode(toCatch.getMessage());
        cout &lt;&lt; "Error during initialization! :\n"
        cout &lt;&lt; "Exception message is: \n"
             &lt;&lt; message &lt;&lt; "\n";
        delete [] message;
        return 1;
    }

    char* xmlFile = "x1.xml";
    SAX2XMLReader* parser = XMLReaderFactory::createXMLReader();
    parser->setFeature(XMLUni::fgSAX2CoreValidation, true)   // optional
    parser->setFeature(XMLUni::fgSAX2CoreNameSpaces, true)   // optional

    DefaultHandler* defaultHandler = new DefaultHandler();
    parser->setContentHandler(defaultHandler);
    parser->setErrorHandler(defaultHandler);

    try {
        parser->parse(xmlFile);
    }
    catch (const XMLException&amp; toCatch) {
        char* message = XMLString::transcode(toCatch.getMessage());
        cout &lt;&lt; "Exception message is: \n"
             &lt;&lt; message &lt;&lt; "\n";
        delete [] message;
        return -1;
    }
    catch (const SAXParseException&amp; toCatch) {
        char* message = XMLString::transcode(toCatch.getMessage());
        cout &lt;&lt; "Exception message is: \n"
             &lt;&lt; message &lt;&lt; "\n";
        delete [] message;
        return -1;
    }
    catch (...) {
        cout &lt;&lt; "Unexpected Exception \n" ;
        return -1;
    }

    delete parser;
    delete defaultHandler;
    return 0;
}</source>
    </s2>

    <anchor name="UsingSAX2API"/>
    <s2 title="Using the SAX2 API">
      <p>The SAX2 API for XML parsers was originally developed for
        Java.  Please be aware that there is no standard SAX2 API for
        C++, and that use of the &XercesCName; SAX2 API does not
        guarantee client code compatibility with other C++ XML
        parsers.</p>

      <p>The SAX2 API presents a callback based API to the parser. An
        application that uses SAX2 provides an instance of a handler
        class to the parser. When the parser detects XML constructs,
        it calls the methods of the handler class, passing them
        information about the construct that was detected. The most
        commonly used handler classes are ContentHandler which is
        called when XML constructs are recognized, and ErrorHandler
        which is called when an error occurs. The header files for the
        various SAX2 handler classes are in
        '&lt;&XercesCInstallDir;>/include/xercesc/sax2'</p>

      <p>As a convenience, &XercesCName; provides the class
        DefaultHandler, which is a single class which is publicly derived
        from all the Handler classes. DefaultHandler's default
        implementation of the handler callback methods is to do
        nothing. A convenient way to get started with &XercesCName; is
        to derive your own handler class from DefaultHandler and override
        just those methods in HandlerBase which you are interested in
        customizing. This simple example shows how to create a handler
        which will print element names, and print fatal error
        messages. The source code for the sample applications show
        additional examples of how to write handler classes.</p>

      <p>This is the header file MySAX2Handler.hpp:</p>
<source>#include &lt;xercesc/sax2/DefaultHandler.hpp>

class MySAX2Handler : public DefaultHandler {
public:
    void startElement(
        const   XMLCh* const    uri,
        const   XMLCh* const    localname,
        const   XMLCh* const    qname,
        const   Attributes&amp;     attrs
    );
    void fatalError(const SAXParseException&amp;);
};</source>

      <p>This is the implementation file MySAX2Handler.cpp:</p>

<source>#include "MySAX2Handler.hpp"
#include &lt;iostream.h>

MySAX2Handler::MySAX2Handler()
{
}

MySAX2Handler::startElement(const   XMLCh* const    uri,
                            const   XMLCh* const    localname,
                            const   XMLCh* const    qname,
                            const   Attributes&amp;     attrs)
{
    char* message = XMLString::transcode(name);
    cout &lt;&lt; "I saw element: "&lt;&lt; message &lt;&lt; endl;
    delete [] message;
}

MySAX2Handler::fatalError(const SAXParseException&amp; exception)
{
    char* message = XMLString::transcode(exception.getMessage());
    cout &lt;&lt; "Fatal Error: " &lt;&lt; message
         &lt;&lt; " at line: " &lt;&lt; exception.getLineNumber()
         &lt;&lt; endl;
}</source>

      <p>The XMLCh and Attributes types are supplied by
        &XercesCName; and are documented in the include
        files. Examples of their usage appear in the source code to
        the sample applications.</p>
    </s2>

    <anchor name="SAX2Features"/>
    <s2 title="Xerces SAX2 Supported Features">

       <p>The behavior of the SAX2XMLReader is dependant on the values of the following features.
       All of the features below can be set using the function <code>SAX2XMLReader::setFeature(cons XMLCh* const, const bool)</code>.
       And can be queried using the function <code>bool SAX2XMLReader::getFeature(const XMLCh* const)</code>.
       </p>
       <p>None of these features can be modified in the middle of a parse, or an exception will be thrown.</p>

        <table>
            <tr><td colspan="2"><em>http://xml.org/sax/features/namespaces</em></td></tr>
            <tr><td><em>true:</em></td><td> Perform Namespace processing (default)</td></tr>
            <tr><td><em>false:</em></td><td> Optionally do not perform Namespace processing</td></tr>
        </table>

        <p/>

        <table>
            <tr><td colspan="2"><em>http://xml.org/sax/features/namespace-prefixes</em></td></tr>
            <tr><td><em>true:</em></td><td> Report the original prefixed names and attributes used for Namespace declarations </td></tr>
            <tr><td><em>false:</em></td><td> Do not report attributes used for Namespace declarations, and optionally do not report original prefixed names. (default)</td></tr>
        </table>

        <p/>

        <table>
            <tr><td colspan="2"><em>http://xml.org/sax/features/validation</em></td></tr>
            <tr><td><em>true:</em></td><td> Report all validation errors. (default)</td></tr>
            <tr><td><em>false:</em></td><td> Do not report validation errors. </td></tr>
        </table>

        <p/>

        <table>
            <tr><td colspan="2"><em>http://apache.org/xml/features/validation/dynamic</em></td></tr>
            <tr><td><em>true:</em></td><td> The parser will validate the document only if a grammar is specified.  (http://xml.org/sax/features/validation must be true)</td></tr>
            <tr><td><em>false:</em></td><td> Validation is determined by the state of the http://xml.org/sax/features/validation feature (default)</td></tr>
        </table>

        <p/>

        <table>
            <tr><td colspan="2"><em>http://apache.org/xml/features/validation/schema</em></td></tr>
            <tr><td><em>true:</em></td><td> Enable the parser's schema support. (default) </td></tr>
            <tr><td><em>false:</em></td><td> Disable the parser's schema support. </td></tr>
        </table>

        <p/>

        <table>
            <tr><td colspan="2"><em>http://apache.org/xml/features/validation/schema-full-checking</em></td></tr>
            <tr><td><em>true:</em></td><td> Enable full schema constraint checking, including checking
                         which may be time-consuming or memory intensive. Currently, particle unique
                         attribution constraint checking and particle derivation restriction checking
                         are controlled by this option. </td></tr>
            <tr><td><em>false:</em></td><td> Disable full schema constraint checking (default). </td></tr>
        </table>

        <p/>

        <table>
            <tr><td colspan="2"><em>http://apache.org/xml/features/nonvalidating/load-external-dtd</em></td></tr>
            <tr><td><em>true:</em></td><td> Load the External DTD (default). </td></tr>
            <tr><td><em>false:</em></td><td> Ignore the external DTD completely.  This feature is
                        ignored and DTD is always loaded when validation is on.</td></tr>
        </table>

        <p/>

        <table>
            <tr><td colspan="2"><em>http://apache.org/xml/features/validation/reuse-grammar</em></td></tr>
            <tr><td><em>true:</em></td><td> The parser will reuse grammar information from previous parses in subsequent parses. </td></tr>
            <tr><td><em>false:</em></td><td> The parser will not reuse any grammar information. (default)</td></tr>
        </table>

        <p/>

        <table>
            <tr><td colspan="2"><em>http://apache.org/xml/features/validation/reuse-validator</em> (deprecated) <br/>
             Please use <em>http://apache.org/xml/features/validation/reuse-grammar</em>
            </td></tr>
            <tr><td><em>true:</em></td><td> The parser will reuse grammar information from previous parses in subsequent parses. </td></tr>
            <tr><td><em>false:</em></td><td> The parser will not reuse any grammar information. (default)</td></tr>
        </table>

    </s2>

    <anchor name="SAX2Properties"/>
    <s2 title="Xerces SAX2 Supported Properties">

       <p>The behavior of the SAX2XMLReader is dependant on the values of the following properties.
       All of the properties below can be set using the function <code>SAX2XMLReader::setProperty(const XMLCh* const, void*)</code>.
       It takes a void pointer as the property value.  Application is required to initialize this void
       pointer to a correct type.  Please check the column "Value Type" below
       to learn exactly what type of property value each property expects for processing.
       Passing a void pointer that was initialized with a wrong type will lead to unexpected result.
       If the same property is set more than once, the last one takes effect.</p>

       <p>Property values can be queried using the function <code>void* SAX2XMLReader::getFeature(const XMLCh* const)</code>.
        The parser owns the returned pointer, and the memory allocated for the returned pointer will
        be destroyed when the parser is deleted.  To ensure accessibility of the returned information after
        the parser is deleted, callers need to copy and store the returned information somewhere else.
        Since the returned pointer is a generic void pointer, check the column "Value Type" below to learn
        exactly what type of object each property returns for replication.</p>

       <p>None of these properties can be modified in the middle of a parse, or an exception will be thrown.</p>

        <table>
            <tr><td colspan="2"><em>http://apache.org/xml/properties/schema/external-schemaLocation</em></td></tr>
            <tr><td><em>Description</em></td><td> The XML Schema Recommendation explicitly states that
                        the inclusion of schemaLocation/ noNamespaceSchemaLocation attributes in the
                        instance document is only a hint; it does not mandate that these attributes
                        must be used to locate schemas.  Similar situation happens to &lt;import&gt;
                        element in schema documents. This property allows the user to specify a list
                        of schemas to use.  If the targetNamespace of a schema specified using this
                        method matches the targetNamespace of a schema occurring in the instance
                        document in schemaLocation attribute, or
                        if the targetNamespace matches the namespace attribute of &lt;import&gt;
                        element, the schema specified by the user using this property will
                        be used (i.e., the schemaLocation attribute in the instance document
                        or on the &lt;import&gt; element will be effectively ignored).</td></tr>
            <tr><td><em>Value</em></td><td> The syntax is the same as for schemaLocation attributes
                             in instance documents: e.g, "http://www.example.com file_name.xsd".
                             The user can specify more than one XML Schema in the list.</td></tr>
            <tr><td><em>Value Type</em></td><td> XMLCh* </td></tr>
        </table>

        <p/>
        <table>
            <tr><td colspan="2"><em>http://apache.org/xml/properties/schema/external-noNamespaceSchemaLocation</em></td></tr>
            <tr><td><em>Description</em></td><td> The XML Schema Recommendation explicitly states that
                        the inclusion of schemaLocation/ noNamespaceSchemaLocation attributes in the
                        instance document is only a hint; it does not mandate that these attributes
                        must be used to locate schemas.  This property allows the user to specify the
                        no target namespace XML Schema Location externally.  If specified, the instance
                        document's noNamespaceSchemaLocation attribute will be effectively ignored.</td></tr>
            <tr><td><em>Value</em></td><td> The syntax is the same as for the noNamespaceSchemaLocation
                        attribute that may occur in an instance document: e.g."file_name.xsd".</td></tr>
            <tr><td><em>Value Type</em></td><td> XMLCh* </td></tr>
        </table>

    </s2>

</s1>
