<?xml version="1.0" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE s1 SYSTEM "./dtd/document.dtd">

<s1 title="Releases">

<s2 title="Xerces-C Version 1.2.0: June 15, 2000">
    <ul>

        <li>DOM: reduced memory usage for elements with no attributes.</li>

        <li>DOMString - add const to return type of <code>const XMLCh
        *DOMString::rawBuffer()</code>.</li>

        <li>Fix crash with Solaris optimized build.  Modified XMLURL.cpp to
        dodge compiler code generation error.</li>

        <li>Bug fix: DOM Attr Specified flag was incorrectly set when cloning or
        importing attributes.</li>

        <li>MSVC projects modified to produce separate debug and release
        versions of Xerces lib and dll.</li>

        <li>Bug fix: DOMPrint, SAXPrint produced garbage output on Solaris.
        Solaris library problem.</li>

        <li>Fixed incorrect error check for end of file in Win32 platfrom
        utils.</li>

        <li>DOMPrint enhancements.  Add options for specifying character
        encoding of the output, better control over escaping of characters,
        better handling of CDATA sections.  Default validation is now
        'auto'.</li>

        <li>XMLFormatter now escapes characters, as reqd., occuring midway in
        strings.</li>

        <li>Bug fix in implementation of
        <code>DOM_Document::GetElementById()</code>.</li>

        <li>Documentation, DTD for source xml files moved into xerces-c project,
        sbk: prefixes removed, xml can now be validated locally.</li>

        <li>Fixed 'fatal error' when 'reusing the validator'.</li>

        <li>Changed <code>#include &lt;memory.h&gt;</code> to
        <code>&lt;string.h&gt;</code> everywhere.</li>

        <li>DOMTest: removed incorrectly failing entity tests.</li>

        <li>Revised implementation of
        <code>DOMDocument::getElementsById()</code>, removed memory leaks,
        new test program for it.</li>

        <li>Bug fix - A PE ref appearing at the start of a skipped conditional
            section was incorrectly being processed rather than ignored.</li>

        <li>Start using the socket based netaccessor by default on most Unix
        platforms.</li>

        <li>Update ICUTransService to work with latest revision of ICU which
            provides a hard linked data DLL. i.e. icudata.dll will be loaded
            when xerces-c is loaded.</li>

        <li>Problem with progressive parsing. parseNext() would through an
            exception when the document contains entities, either internal or
            external.</li>

        <li>Add missing validity checks for stand-alone documents, character
        range and Well-formed parsed entities.</li>

        <li>Fix: compilation problems on MSVC 5.</li>

        <li>Fix: XMLReader defect.</li>

        <li>Fix: problem with Windows filenames containing '\' in Japanese and
        Korean encodings.</li>

        <li>Memory Cleanup. XMLPlatformUtils::Terminate() deletes all lazily
        allocated memory.</li>

        <li>Fixed defect in progressive parsing 'parseNext()'.</li>

        <li>Fixed Solaris build problems with static character constants.</li>

        <li>Reduced memory usage for DOM Attributes.</li>

        <li>New runConfigure options -P and -C.</li>

        <li>Memory leaks in TransService.</li>

        <li>DOM - storage requirements for nodes substantially reduced.</li>

        <li>Added DOM XMLDecl node type; provides access to XML
        declaration.</li>

        <li>Added DOM access to internal DTD subset (DOM Level 2 feature).</li>

        <li>API document generation changed to DOxygen from Doc++.</li>

        <li>Full support for DOM_EntityReference, DOM_Entity and
        DOM_DocumentType introduced.</li>

        <li>Don't allow spaces before PI target.</li>

        <li>Follow the SMP/E procedures for the OS/390 BATCH install.</li>

        <li>Auto-validate mode. Validate only when a DTD is present.</li>

        <li>If a SAX error handler is installed, then the resetErrors() event
        handler should call the one on the installed SAX error handler.</li>

        <li>Allow an empty DOCTYPE declaration, with just the root name.</li>

        <li>Add low level support for transcoding XML output to different
        character encodings.</li>

        <li>DOM node memory footprint reduction.</li>

        <li>Fixed hanging bug in character transcoding.</li>

        <li>Enable installation of DTDHandler on SAX parser.</li>

        <li>Support for PTX platform.</li>

        <li>IRIX 6.5 port.</li>

        <li>COM wrappers.</li>

        <li>DOM_Document::GetElementsByTagId() added.</li>

        <li>DOM: support for identifying &quot;ignorable white space&quot; text
        nodes.</li>

        <li>URL Net Accessor added.</li>

        <li>Fix null pointer exception with some bad documents.</li>

        <li>Initial support for two-way transcoding.</li>

        <li>Intrinsic transcoding table generation utility added.</li>

        <li>UNIX build: Now generates object files in platform-specific
        directories.</li>

        <li>Fix GCC build problem: Changed XML_GNUG to XML_GCC.</li>

        <li>Fixed #54. Changed self-assignment to now use the parameter
        value.</li>

        <li>Fix bug # 19, add const keyword to API. As a result, update test
        case.</li>

        <li>DOM: 'specified' flag of attributes now set correctly.</li>

        <li>Some fixes for content models that have multiple, trailing, empty PE
            refs (for content model extension).</li>

        <li>First cut for additions to Win32 xcode. Based very loosely on a
            prototype from Eric Ulevik.</li>

        <li>Fixed a bug in SimpleContentModel that allowed an &lt;a/&gt; to be
        taken as valid for a content model of (a,b).</li>

        <li>Added a scanReset()/parseReset() method to the scanner and parsers,
        to allow for reset after early exit from a progressive parse. Added
        calls to new Terminate() call to all of the samples. Improved
        documentation in SAX and DOM parsers.</li>

        <li>Change 'XML4C' to 'Xerces' in many places.</li>

        <li>Add a cleanup method to XMLPlatformUtils.</li>

        <li>Implement the Locator scheme for SAX.</li>

        <li>Add a -n option to most of the samples, to enable namespaces.</li>

        <li>Fix an error where XMLScanner::parseNext() was falling through on an
        exception instead of return a failure.</li>

        <li>Implement the specialized string loading for Win98, since
        LoadStringW() doesn't work on 98 and makes the loaded error text from
        the Win32 message loader come out junk.</li>

        <li>Fix: error when two trailing entity references in a content model,
        like: &lt;!ELEMENT foo (a|b|c|d|e %one;%two;)*&gt;</li>

    </ul>
</s2>

<s2 title="Xerces-C Version 1.1.0: February 28, 2000">
        <ul>
        <li>Simplified platform support (removed need to support local standard output streams or to find the location of the parser DLL/SharedLib.)</li>
                <li>Added support for the NetAccessor plug in abstraction, which allows the parser to support HTTP/FTP based data sources</li>
                <li>Added EBCDIC-US and ISO-8859-1 as intrinsic encodings</li>
                <li>Added more DOM Level II features</li>
                <li>Support for ICU 1.4, which makes &XercesCName; Unicode 3.0 compliant when using ICU</li>
                <li>New samples and tests (DOM test, programmatic DOM sample, thread test)</li>
                <li>Added support for multiply nested entities using relative paths or URLs</li>
                <li>Significant internal architecture improvements in the handling of encodings and transcoding services.</li>
        </ul>
    </s2>
    <s2 title="Xerces-C Version 1.0.1: December 15, 1999">
        <ul>
            <li>Port to Solaris.</li>
            <li>Improved error recovery and clarified error messages.</li>
            <li>Added DOMTest program.</li>
        </ul>
    </s2>

    <s2 title="&XercesCFullName; Version 1.0.0: December 7, 1999">
        <ul>
            <li>Released &XercesCName; after incorporating ICU as a value-added plug-in.</li>
            <li>Has bug fixes, better conformance, better speed and cleaner internal internal architecture</li>
            <li>Three additional samples added: PParse, StdInParse and EnumVal</li>
            <li>Experimental DOM Level 2 support</li>
            <li>Support for namespaces</li>
            <li>Loadable message text enabling future translations to be easily plugged-in</li>
            <li>Pluggable validators</li>
            <li>Pluggable transcoders</li>
            <li>Reorganized the util directory to better manage different platforms and compilers</li>
        </ul>
    </s2>

    <s2 title="Xerces-C BETA November 5, 1999">
        <ul>
            <li>Created initial code base derived from IBM's XML4C Version 2.0</li>
            <li>Modified documentation to reflect new name (Xerces-C)</li>
        </ul>
    </s2>
</s1>
