<?xml version="1.0" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE s1 SYSTEM "./dtd/document.dtd">

<s1 title="&XercesCName; Samples">

    <s2 title="Building the Samples">
    <p>&XercesCName; comes packaged with ten sample applications that
    demonstrate salient features of the parser using simple
    applications written on top of the SAX and DOM APIs provided by
    the parser.</p>

    <p>Once you have set up your PATH variable, you can run the
    samples by opening a command window (or your shell prompt for
    UNIX environments). Sample XML data files are provided in the
    samples/data directory.</p>

    <p>The installation process for the samples is same on all UNIX
    platforms.
    Note that <em>runConfigure</em> is just a helper script and you are free to
    use <em>./configure</em> with the correct parameters to make it work
    on any platform-compiler combination of your choice. The script needs the following parameters:
    </p>
<source>Usage: runConfigure "options"
       where options may be any of the following:
       -p &lt;platform&gt; (accepts 'aix', 'linux', 'solaris', 'hp-10', 'hp-11')
       -c &lt;C compiler name&gt; (e.g. gcc, xlc_r, cc or aCC)
       -x &lt;C++ compiler name&gt; (e.g. g++, xlC_r, CC or aCC)
       -d (specifies that you want to build debug version)
       -h (get help on the above commands)</source>

    <note><em>NOTE:</em>The code samples in this section assume that you are are working on the Linux binary drop.
    If you are using some other UNIX flavor, please replace '-linux' with the appropriate
    platform name in the code samples.</note>

    </s2>

    <s2 title="Building the Samples for OS2">

    <p>Building the Xerces-C samples using IBM Visual Age C++ Professional 4.0
    for OS/2 (VAC++).</p>

     <ul>
     <li> In the <code>XercesCSrcInstallDir;\samples\Projects\OS2\VACPP40</code> directory,
     find and edit the VAC++ configuration file <code>basedir.icc</code>.</li>

     <li>All of the directories used to build the samples are defined in
     <code>basedir.icc</code>. You need to edit the directories to match your system.
     Here are the directories you need to assign:

            SRC_DIR -- <code>XercesCSrcInstallDir;</code>
                       This is where VAC++ should look to find the samples
                       directories containing the source files.
            BASE_DIR -- The install directory <code>XercesCSrcInstallDir;</code>.
            		VAC++ will store the compiled samples in the <code>bin</code>
            		directory under BASE_DIR. It will also look for the
            		<code>xerces-c.lib</code> file in the <code>lib</code> directory under BASE_DIR.

        Other directories are set based on these two. You can choose to override them
        if you wish.</li>

     <li>Save <code>basedir.icc</code></li>

     <li>Start the Command Line in the VAC++ folder.</li>

     <li>Navigate to the <code>XercesCSrcInstallDir;\samples\Projects\OS2\VACPP40</code> directory.</li>

     <li>Run <code>bldsamples.cmd</code></li>

     <li>When <code>build.cmd</code> finishes, review the file <code>compiler.errors</code>.
     This file should contain only informational messages, almost all complaining about constant
        values in comparisons.</li>

     <li>You should now have several executable files.</li>

    </ul>

    <p>Rebuilding the Configuration Files</p>

    <p>Although it shouldn't be necessary, if you want to rebuild the VAC++
    configuration files, you'll need to have Object Rexx running on your system:<p>

    <ul>
     <li> If you are not currently running Object Rexx, run the SWITCHRX command from
        a command line, answer "yes" to switching to Object Rexx, and follow the
        instructions to reboot. (Note: You can switch back to "Classic Rexx" by
        running SWITCHRX again. But you probably won't need to switch back since
        Object Rexx runs almost 100% of Classic Rexx programs.)</li>

     <li>In the Projects\OS2\VACPP40 directory, run genICC.cmd. This builds the VAC++
        configuration files for the samples you have on your system.</li>


      <li>Go to the first step above in the "Building asmples for OS/2" section.</li>
	</ul>
   </s2>

    <s2 title="Running the Samples">

    <p>The sample applications are dependent on the &XercesCName; shared library
		(and could also depend on the ICU library if you built &XercesCName; with ICU).
		Therefore, on Windows platforms you must make sure that your <code>PATH</code>
		environment variable is set properly to pick up these shared libraries at
		runtime.</p>

		<p>On UNIX platforms you must ensure that <ref>LIBPATH</ref>
		environment variable is set properly to pick up the shared libraries at
		runtime. (UNIX gurus will understand here that <ref>LIBPATH</ref> actually
		translates to <em>LD_LIBRARY_PATH</em> on Solaris and Linux, <em>SHLIB_PATH</em> on HP-UX
		and stays as <em>LIBPATH</em> on AIX).</p>

		<p>To set you LIBPATH (on AIX for example), you would type:</p>
<source>export LIBPATH=&XercesCInstallDir;/lib:$LIBPATH</source>

		<s3 title="&XercesCName; Samples">
			<ul>
				<li><link idref="saxcount">SAXCount</link>
					<br/>SAXCount counts the elements, attributes, spaces and
					characters in an XML file.</li>
				<li><link idref="saxprint">SAXPrint</link>
					<br/>SAXPrint parses an XML file and prints it out.</li>
				<li><link idref="domcount">DOMCount</link>
					<br/>DOMCount counts the elements in a XML file.</li>
				<li><link idref="domprint">DOMPrint</link>
					<br/>DOMPrint parses an XML file and prints it out.</li>
				<li><link idref="memparse">MemParse</link>
					<br/>MemParse parses XML in a memory buffer, outputing the number of elements and attributes.</li>
				<li><link idref="redirect">Redirect</link>
					<br/>Redirect redirects the input stream for external entities.</li>
				<li><link idref="pparse">PParse</link>
					<br/>PParse demonstrates progressive parsing.</li>
				<li><link idref="stdinparse">StdInParse</link>
					<br/>StdInParse demonstrates streaming XML data from standard input.</li>
				<li><link idref="enumval">EnumVal</link>
					<br/>EnumVal shows how to enumerate the markup decls in a DTD Validator.</li>
				<li><link idref="createdoc">CreateDOMDocument</link>
					<br/>CreateDOMDocument creates a DOM tree in memory from scratch.</li>
			</ul>
		</s3>
    </s2>
</s1>
