<?xml version="1.0" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE s1 SYSTEM "./dtd/document.dtd">
<s1 title="Schema">
       <s2 title="Disclaimer">
		<p>Schema is not fully supported in Xerces-C yet.  But an
               experimental implementation of a subset of the W3C XML
               Schema language is now available for review in Xerces1.5.            
               You should not consider this implementation complete or 
			   correct. The limitations of this implementation are 
			   detailed below.  Please read this document before using 
			   Xerces 1.5.
               </p>
       </s2>
       <s2 title="Introduction">
               <p>The Xerces 1.5 contains an implementation
               of a subset of the W3C XML Schema Language as specified
               in the 2 May 2001 Recommendation for <jump
               href="http://www.w3.org/TR/xmlschema-1/">Structures</jump>
               and <jump href="http://www.w3.org/TR/xmlschema-2/">
               Datatypes</jump>. The parsers contained in this package are
               able to read and validate XML documents with the grammar specified
               in either DTD or XML Schema format.
               </p>
               <p>We intend to update this package until it implements all
               the functionality of the current XML Schema Recommendation.
               If you are interested in a particular unimplemented feature, or
               if you have any feedback on the implementation design,
               we welcome your input to the <jump href="mailto:&XercesCEmailAddress;">
               Xerces-C mailing list &XercesCEmailAddress; </jump> .
               </p>
       </s2>
       <s2 title="Limitations">
               <p>The XML Schema implementation in the Xerces 1.5 is a
               subset of the features defined in the 2 May 2001 XML Schema Recommendation.
               </p>
       </s2>

       <anchor name="supportedFeature"/>
       <s2 title='Features/Datatypes Supported'>
               <ul>
                       <li>Partial Simple type support </li>
                       <ul>
                               <li> Yes: atomic simple type </li>
                               <li> No: union and list </li>
                       </ul>
                       <li>Partial Complex type suppport </li>
                       <ul>
                                <li> Yes: choice, sequence </li>
                                <li> No: group, all </li>
                       </ul>
                       <li>Element and Attribute Declaration </li>
                       <ul>
                                <li> No: any/anyAttribute </li>
                       </ul>
                       <li>SubsitutionGroup</li>
                       <li>Subset of Built-in Datatypes</li>
                       <ul>
                                <li>Primitive Datatypes: string, boolean, decimal, hexbinary, base64binary</li>
                                <li>Derived Datatypes: integer</li>
                       </ul>
                       <li>xsi Markup</li>
                       <ul>
                                <li>Yes: xsi:nil</li>
                                <li>Yes: xsi:schemaLocation and xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation</li>
                                <li>No: xsi:type</li>
                       </ul>
               </ul>


               <p> Additional Experimental Features (not tested and subject to change, use as is)</p>
               <ul>
                       <li>Complex type derivation support (simpleContent and complexContent).</li>
                       <li>Element and attribute re-use using "ref".</li>
                       <li>Include support</li>
                       <li>Import Support</li>
               </ul>

               <p>Other features in the Schema recommendation such as "redefine",
               "identity constraints" and others which are not mentioned above, are not supported
               yet. But development is continuing and we target to implement all the
               features of the current XML Schema Recommendation before end of this year.
               Please note that the date is tentative and subject to change.
               </p>
       </s2>

       <s2 title="Other Limitations">
               <p>The schema must be specified by the xsi:schemaLocation or
               xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation attribute on the root
               element of the document. The xsi prefix must be bound to the
               Schema document instance namespace, as specified by the
               Recommendation. See the sample provided in the Usage section.
               </p>
       </s2>

       <anchor name="usage"/>
       <s2 title="Usage">
               <p>XML document specifies the XML Schema grammar location in the
               xsi:schemaLocation attribute attached to the root / top-level element.
               Here is an example with no target namspace:
               </p>
<source>&lt;?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?&gt;
&lt;personnel xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	   xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation='personal.xsd'&gt;
...
&lt;/personnel&gt;
</source>
               <p>Please see the sample file, 'samples/data/personal-schema.xml' for
               further detail.  And review the sample file 'samples/data/personal.xsd'
               for an example of an XML Schema grammar.
               </p>
               <p>Here is an example how to turn on schema processing in DOMParser
               (default is off).  Note that you must also turn on namespace support
               (default is off) for schema processing.
               </p>
<source>// Instantiate the DOM parser.
DOMParser parser;
parser.setDoNamespaces(true);
parser.setDoSchema(true);
parser.parse(xmlFile);
</source>
               <p>Usage in SAXParser is similar, please refer to the
               sample program 'samples/SAXCount/SAXCount.cpp' for further reference.
               </p>
               <p>Here is an example how to turn on schema processing in SAX2XMLReader
               (default is on).  Note that namespace must be on (default is on) as well.
               </p>
<source>SAX2XMLReader* parser = XMLReaderFactory::createXMLReader();
parser->setFeature(XMLString::transcode("http://xml.org/sax/features/namespaces"), true);
parser->setFeature(XMLString::transcode("http://apache.org/xml/features/validation/schema"), true);
parser->parse(xmlFile);
</source>
       </s2>
</s1>
